music
音楽
The Central Research Institute's
中央研究所の
nine-month knowledge review
9か月間の知識のレビュー
speech will begin.
スピーチが始まります。
Let's welcome Director Wang Yu
王宇監督をお迎えしましょう
to give us a round of applause.
拍手を送ります。
applause
拍手
Good evening, everyone.
皆さん、こんばんわ。
Today, I think it's
今日はそう思います
Vice President Wang Fansheng came to host
王範生副主席が主催者として来日
he is also a historian
彼は歴史家でもあります
So you can put this
それで、これを置くことができます
It is also a good research partner with today's speaker
今日の講演者との良い研究パートナーでもあります
but today he is sick
しかし今日彼は病気です
So I'm here to introduce
そこで紹介するのがここです
but i want to have a
でも私は欲しいです
I'm the first to have the same sex with him
まず私は彼と同性です
Second, I also care about history
次に、私は歴史にも関心があります
So on this principle
したがって、この原則に基づいて
Let me briefly introduce to you
簡単にご紹介させていただきます
our keynote speaker today
今日の基調講演者
Today's speaker is Academician Wang Mingke
今日の講演者は王明科院士です。
Academician Wang Mingke graduated from
王明科院士が卒業
Department of History, National Taiwan Normal University
国立台湾師範大学史学科
Earn a Ph.D. from Harvard University
ハーバード大学で博士号を取得する
since 84
84年以来
He has been in the Institute's History Research
彼は研究所の歴史研究に携わっています
language institute
語学学校
In fact, the Institute of History
実は歴史研究所は、
The original research institute is also the largest and relatively old one in our institute.
元の研究所も当研究所の中で最大規模で比較的古い研究所です。
He used to teach in other than Academia Sinica
彼はかつて中央研究院以外で教鞭をとっていた
He also taught at National Taiwan University, Soochow University, Chung Hsing University
国立台湾大学、東州大学、中興大学でも教鞭を執った
He was also transferred to Chung Hsing University as the Dean of Culture and Propaganda
彼はまた、文化宣伝学部長として中興大学に転任した。
That was 2010 to 2013
それは2010年から2013年でした
In 2014, that is, last year, he was elected as a Third World Academician of the Institute of Election Research
2014 年、つまり昨年、彼は選挙研究所の第三世界会員に選出されました。
That's also currently a special review researcher at our Institute of History.
それは現在、歴史研究所の特別評論研究員でもあります。
Dr. Wang from 94 to 2003
王博士 94 年から 2003 年まで
I have been to western Sichuan many times, and there are three companies in Minjiang who have accumulated one-year experience
私は四川省西部には何度も行っていますが、閩江には1年の経験を積んだ会社が3社あります。
gun for field research
フィールド調査用の銃
From zero three to zero seven
ゼロスリーからゼロセブンまで
Sichuan, Inner Mongolia, Xinjiang, Qinghai
四川省、内モンゴル自治区、新疆ウイグル自治区、青海省
Inspect the local environment
ローカル環境を検査する
The ecology of human beings with Youmu
妖夢とともに語る人類の生態
2007 to present
2007年から現在まで
His field research moved to
彼のフィールド研究は次の場所に移りました。
Sichuan, Liangshan, etc.
四川省、梁山市など
minority autonomous regions
少数民族自治区
Tibetan
チベット語
Yizu etc.
伊豆など
The subject of study is history
研究テーマは歴史です
Multifaceted local
多面的な地域
and their living in human
そして人間の中での彼らの暮らし
The meaning of social development
社会発展の意味
so
それで
This is also very special
これもとても特別なことです
So the number of people who signed up today is
さて、今日登録した人の数は
Far more than
はるかにそれ以上
Over the years
長年にわたって
If it is not enough to do, there is a TV broadcast outside
それでも足りない場合は、外でテレビ放送があります
The results of Dr. Wang's field research on Jiangzhang ethnic minorities
王博士による江漳族少数民族の現地調査の結果
It also illustrates the historical process of China and its fringe interdependence.
また、中国の歴史的過程と周辺地域の相互依存関係も示しています。
The results are also shown in a series of recent works
その成果は最近の一連の作品にも表れています
From 1997 published the edge of Huaxia
1997年から華夏の端を出版
2003 Guns between Han and Tibet
2003 年 漢とチベットの間で銃乱射事件
2006 is Heroes Ancestors and Brothers Democracy
2006 年は英雄の祖先と兄弟の民主主義
2009 is the nomad's choice
2009 年は遊牧民の選択です
This year he published Reflection on History and Historiography Reflection
今年、彼は『歴史の省察』と『歴史学の省察』を出版しました。
If you are interested in this series of works
このシリーズの作品に興味のある方は
can be used as a reference
参考として使用できます
Then I'll stop talking nonsense, please
じゃあ、くだらない話はやめてください
Dr. Wang started his speech
王博士がスピーチを始めた
I want to thank Dean Wang for introducing me.
私を紹介してくれた Dean Wang に感謝します。
I also want to thank the Central Plains Academy for giving me this opportunity
また、このような機会を与えてくれたセントラル・プレーンズ・アカデミーにも感謝したいと思います。
name feasting on knowledge
知識を楽しむ名前
to put some of my research
私の研究の一部を載せるために
Some small thoughts to share with you
あなたと共有したい小さな考え
Since it's a feast
お祭りなので
i think we all take it easy
みんなゆっくりしてると思うよ
But today so many people came to this speech
しかし今日はとても多くの人がこのスピーチに来ました
first i think
まず私は思います
Maybe I got the title right
たぶんタイトルは合ってると思う
everybody really cares about history
みんな本当に歴史に興味があるんだね
let's see
どれどれ
Actually what I'm going to talk about is
実際に私が話そうとしていることは、
You know what history we care about
私たちがどのような歴史を大切にしているか知っていますか
Because we knew from the beginning that people cared about history
人々が歴史を重視していることを最初から知っていたからです
All right
わかった
Recently, everyone knows that in Taiwan some
最近、台湾では誰もが知っています。
Controversy over the History Curriculum of the State Religion
国教の歴史カリキュラムをめぐる論争
There is also a grand commemoration of the 70th anniversary of the Anti-Japanese War in mainland China
中国本土では抗日戦争70周年の盛大な記念式典も行われている
international controversy
国際論争
Looks like it's all history's fault
どうやら全ては歴史のせいのようだ
So what kind of history do we care about?
それでは、私たちはどのような歴史を気にするのでしょうか？
Is it a historical fact?
それは歴史的事実ですか？
Or how the historical facts should be written and presented
あるいは歴史的事実はどのように書かれ、提示されるべきか
Or we really should be vested in history
あるいは、私たちは本当に歴史の中に属すべきだ
strengthened
被強化
let everyone
みんなにさせて
Let us all know the lessons of history
歴史の教訓をみんなで知ろう
or history should be forgotten
さもなければ歴史は忘れられるべきだ
Don't be a burden to contemporary people
現代人の負担にならないように
That
それか
I guess someone might say I don't care about history
歴史など気にしないと言う人もいるかもしれない
Is it true that some people don't care about history?
歴史を気にしない人がいるというのは本当ですか？
i don't think so
私はそうは思わない
I'll tell you in a minute because we didn't
そうしなかったので、すぐに教えます
Everyone lives in a world created by history
誰もが歴史が作った世界に生きている
At least some of you care about the history of the stock
少なくとも一部の人は株式の歴史に興味を持っています
The history of the company's earnings and its own adjustment history
同社の業績推移と自社の調整の歴史
and i think
で思うんですけど
Many couples care about each other's social history before marriage
多くのカップルは結婚前にお互いの社会的経歴を気にします
so
それで
What is the history we care about?
私たちが大切にしている歴史とは何でしょうか？
a very interesting phenomenon
とても興味深い現象です
It is the history in Chinese and the history in English
中国語の歴史と英語の歴史です
Both are one word with two meanings
どちらも 2 つの意味を持つ 1 つの単語です
One meaning is those things that really happened in the past
一つの意味は、過去に実際に起こったことです
there is another meaning
別の意味があります
It is people's memories, recollections and narratives of the past.
人々の過去の記憶、回想、物語
In fact, these two are completely different things
実はこの二つは全くの別物です
Why is it the same word in both English and Chinese?
なぜ英語と中国語で同じ言葉なのでしょうか？
In fact, there is a French scholar from all over the world, Portico
実は世界中から集まったフランス人学者、ポルティコがいる。
have mentioned this
これについて言及しました
He said that we people live in the real world created by history
彼は、私たち人間は歴史が作り出した現実の世界に生きていると言いました。
Is the cause of history
歴史の原因は
So we also write history in this world
だから私たちもこの世界に歴史を刻んでいる
is making history
歴史を作っている
So we kind of mix those two things up
したがって、これら 2 つのことを混ぜ合わせて考えます
so we think
それで私たちは考えます
Our historical facts and representations of historical memory
私たちの歴史的事実と歴史的記憶の表現
Seems like they're all the same thing
どれも同じもののようですね
so good
とても良い
So let's talk about history that people care about
それでは人々が関心を寄せている歴史について話しましょう
In fact, it is just the history I used to add the quartition mark
実際、これは私がクォーションマークを追加するために使用した単なる履歴です
To refer to people's memory and expression of the past
人々の過去の記憶や表現に言及すること
Because no matter how many real things that happened in the past
過去にどれだけ現実の出来事があったとしても
No matter how accurately we reconstruct and state the facts of what happened in the past
過去に起こった事実をどれだけ正確に再現して述べたとしても
It's all about our choices about these facts
すべてはこれらの歴史的事実に関する私たちの選択にかかっています
and how do we express it
そしてそれをどう表現するか
Our expressions relate to our words
私たちの表現は言葉と関係しています
arrangement with law
法律との取り決め
These are deeply influenced by our society
これらは私たちの社会に深く影響されています
and the influence of our individual situations in society
そして社会における私たちの個々の状況の影響
So because of history and the social reality people live in and the identity of the individual during the period?
では、歴史や人々が生きてきた社会的現実、そしてその時代の個人のアイデンティティのためでしょうか？
closely related
密接に関係している
So simply speaking, we live in a society created by history.
つまり、簡単に言えば、私たちは歴史によって作られた社会に住んでいます。
especially living within the personal identities that history has created
特に歴史が生み出した個人のアイデンティティの中で生きている
So it is difficult for us to recognize the influence of society on the construction of history
したがって、歴史の構築に対する社会の影響を認識することは困難です
Even because of this, we don't really have a very good understanding of the social reality we live in.
このような理由でさえ、私たちは自分たちが住んでいる社会の現実をあまりよく理解していません。
So I'm going to explain my arguments to you
それで、私の主張をあなたに説明します
Then my method is a very special
それから私の方法は非常に特殊です
This is related to my research
これは私の研究に関連しています
It is from a society that is very strange and strange to us
それは私たちにとって非常に奇妙で奇妙な社会からのものです
Get started with some history as locals believe
地元の人々が信じている歴史について学びましょう
to show how they live in the history of their own making
自分たちが作った歴史の中で彼らがどのように生きているかを示すために
and related reality
そしてそれに関連する現実
How do they care about history and argue with others about history?
彼らはどのようにして歴史に関心を持ち、歴史について他の人と議論するのでしょうか?
that's what i said
それは私が言ったことです
Walter is familiar with
ウォルターはよく知っています
This is what I spent more than ten years
これが私が10年以上費やしたことです
Research done on the Sichuan-Tibet Plateau
四川チベット高原で行われた研究
But that's only half of my research
しかし、それは私の研究の半分にすぎません
my other half
私の他の半分
is the logic i use like this
私が使うロジックはこんな感じですか
Let's rethink the records in Chinese historical documents
中国の歴史文書の記録を再考してみよう
So this means
つまり、これは意味します
I'm the same in this speech
このスピーチでは私も同じです
When I turn the stranger into the familiar
見知らぬ人を慣れ親しんだ人に変えるとき
I want to explain what we are familiar with
私たちがよく知っていることを説明したい
The history of what you believe in and what you care about
あなたが何を信じ、何を大切にしているのかの歴史
peculiar in fact
実は奇妙な
He was identified under a specific social situation
彼は特定の社会的状況の下で特定された
They also reinforce a social situation like this
彼らはまた、このような社会状況を強化します
This is Huashu Sivict
フアシュ・シヴィシットです
My example is the eastern edge of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau
私の例は青海チベット高原の東端です。
Look at these three circles
この3つの円を見てください
You can see that Chengdu is in this place
成都がこの場所にあることがわかります
This place is the Chengdu Plain
ここは成都平原です
Its height is about 6,000 meters
その高さは約6,000メートルです
instead of around 600 meters
約600メートルではなく
what about this place
この場所はどうですか
This place is Songpan plateau here
ここが松潘高原です
What about the plateau area here?
ここの高原地帯はどうでしょうか？
about 3600 meters
約3,600メートル
In other words, the drop is 3,000 meters
つまり落差は3,000メートル
so this place
それでこの場所
Mountains and heavy lakes almost like steps
まるで階段のように続く山と重い湖
so what about this place
それで、この場所はどうですか
This is caused by the extrusion of these two road blocks.
これは、これら 2 つの道路ブロックの押し出しによって引き起こされます。
Zhe District
浙区
So there is a very rich humanities here
ここには非常に豊かな人文科学があります
natural geographical landscape, plants
自然の地理的景観、植物
It's the one over here and it's very rich
それはここのもので、とても豊かです
Then the gun bamboo I want to talk about first I want to introduce is here
それではまず最初にご紹介したい銃竹はこちらです
Then the Jiarong Zangzhu I introduced is here
次に、Jiaron Zangzhuをここで紹介しました
Here are two mountains and one bamboo
ここに二つの山と一本の竹があります
so in this area
だからこの地域では
In fact, everyone should not think that these are three ethnic groups
実際、誰もがこれらが 3 つの民族グループであると考えるべきではありません
In fact, before the ethnic surveys in mainland China identified and classified
実際、中国本土での民族調査が行われる前に、
The people here are especially Tibetan bamboo and spear bamboo
ここの人々は特にチベット竹と槍竹です
They all said that we have never heard of Tibetan bamboo
彼らは皆、チベットの竹について聞いたことがないと言った
never heard
聞いたことがない
This is the name someone gave us
これは誰かが私たちに付けた名前です
we have to accept
私たちは受け入れなければなりません
So there are actually a lot of ethnic groups here
ここには実際に多くの民族グループがいます
people in every little valley
あらゆる小さな谷の人々
He thinks he is a special group
彼は自分が特別なグループだと思っている
And it has nothing to do with the people around
そしてそれは周りの人たちとは何の関係もありません
So this is my field
だからここは私のフィールドです
My field is a multi-point field
私のフィールドはマルチポイントフィールドです
That is to say, this green
つまりこの緑は
is the field point representing me
私を表すフィールドポイントです
This is the same as the so-called squatting of many anthropologists
これは多くの人類学者のいわゆる不法占拠と同じです
At one point the ones that do it are not quite the same
ある時点で、それを行う人はまったく同じではありません
So my research on gun bamboo
ということで、銃竹に関する私の研究
The name of the book is Guns Between Han and Tibet
本の名前は「漢とチベットの間の銃」
so you look at these two pictures
それで、この2枚の写真を見てください
you can see what's up with them
彼らがどうなっているのかがわかります
This is the spear bamboo in the east of Beichuan
これは北川東部の槍竹です
except me
私を除いて
was very young at that time
当時はとても若かった
so you see all of them
それで全部見えますよ
Chairs made no matter what people wear
人が何を着ても椅子は作られます
if you can see clearly
はっきりと見えるなら
next to the house or something
家の隣か何か
It's exactly the same as Han bamboo
漢竹と全く同じです
It is no different from Han bamboo in western Sichuan
四川西部の漢竹と何ら変わりません
This place is the westernmost Xiaoxingou
ここは小興溝の最西端です
I do a lot of research here
ここでたくさんの研究をしています
Gun bamboo here
ガンバンブーはこちら
This is exactly the same as the Tibetan bamboo next to it
これは隣のチベット竹と全く同じです
So in the middle is a little bit of excessive past
だから真ん中には少し過剰な過去がある
so this is a
これは
So among the ethnic minorities in mainland China
つまり、中国本土の少数民族の間では
It is a very strange nation
とても不思議な国ですね
if we think of it as a nation
国家として考えたら
so you look at its environment
それでその環境を見てみます
Where they live is high mountains and deep valleys
彼らが住んでいる場所は高い山と深い谷です
this is a ditch
これは溝です
It is a small tributary of the Min River
閩江の小さな支流です
people
人々
Look here is a village
見てください、ここに村があります
This is Shanlonggou
ここはシャンロンゴウです
The location of this village is very high
この村の位置はとても高いです
so when you get here
だからここに着いたら
you can't help but wonder
不思議に思わずにはいられない
In other words, why do people live here?
言い換えれば、なぜ人はここに住んでいるのか？
In fact, the simplest reason
実は一番単純な理由としては
just for safety
安全のためだけに
pursue this
これを追求する
see you later
また後で
what about their lives here
ここでの彼らの生活はどうなるのか
They are plural to exploit a valley
彼らは谷を開拓するために複数形です
vertical
垂直的
From this farm next to my home
私の家の隣のこの農場から
To this place where wool cattle are raised on the mountain
山の上で毛牛を育てるこの場所へ
And then hunt the young ones will go out to hunt in the winter
そして狩りをする若者たちは冬に狩りに出かけるでしょう
Everyone, look at this photo and you can see it again
皆さん、この写真を見てください、またわかります
Their hairy cattle are almost like bison
彼らの毛むくじゃらの牛はまるでバイソンのようです
Look here we brought a dog up here
見てください、私たちはここに犬を連れてきました
So the leading bull comes to the dog
それで先頭の雄牛が犬のところに来る
Then the young bulls count as a circle
次に、若い雄牛を円として数えます
Keep the cow and calf behind
牛と子牛を後ろに置いてください
This is the habit is exactly the same as that
これはあの習慣と全く同じです
like the buffalo you saw in yerston
ヤーストンで見たバッファローのように
this is their home
ここが彼らの家です
This is Xiaoxingou Aiqi Village
ここは小興溝愛奇村です
farmland near their home
自宅近くの農地
This is their Jianjun mushroom on the mountain
これは山にあるジャンジュンキノコです
Basically you occupy that little ditch
基本的にあなたはその小さな溝を占領します
Probably life without fish
おそらく魚のいない人生
But resources are very tight
しかし資源は非常に逼迫している
Every resource boundary here is very important
ここでのすべてのリソース境界は非常に重要です
so you see from this picture you can tell
この写真を見れば分かると思いますが、
Their tense relationship over this competition for resources
資源をめぐる競争をめぐる彼らの緊張関係
This is the black tiger
これがブラックタイガーです
That black tiger is here you see it's built on a ridge
あのブラックタイガーがここにいるよ、尾根の上に建っているのがわかるだろう
There are very oblique fights on both sides
双方とも非常に不当な戦いが行われている
Then this ridge was covered with some
するとこの尾根は何かで覆われてしまいました。
Everyone looks like a chimney thing
みんな煙突みたいだ
that's not a chimney
それは煙突ではありません
That's a defensive tower
それは防御塔です
So you look at Chinese literature
それで中国文学を見てみると
It is said that the black tiger gun was overturned in the Ming and Qing dynasties
黒虎銃は明清時代に転覆されたと言われている
is famously brutal
残忍であることで有名な
So wait a minute and I'll repeat
ちょっと待ってください、繰り返します
emphasize this to everyone
これをみんなに強調してください
Documentation you have seen
あなたが見たドキュメント
even the world you see
あなたが見ている世界さえも
all other appearances
他のすべての表面的な現象
it's all a representation
それはすべてサインです
What is the original image behind it?
その背後にある元のイメージは何ですか？
as you can see in this picture
この写真でわかるように
That is, the competition for resources is very fierce.
つまり、資源をめぐる競争は非常に激しいのです。
People are in a very tense state
人々は非常に緊張した状態にあります
This is Yonghegou, everyone sees it is the same
これは雍和溝です、誰が見ても同じです
The houses are tightly packed together, on the hillside
丘の中腹に家がびっしりと建っている
Min Jiang's Ziliu at the bottom is still at the bottom
最下位の岷江紫柳は依然として最下位である
It's also winter time and this farmland is dry
冬でもあり、この農地は乾燥している
This is Puxigou in Li County, you can see it more clearly
ここは李県の浦西溝です、もっとはっきり見えます
This is a village, all the houses are tightly grouped together
ここは村、家々がぎっしりと集まっている
And it's far from the valley below
そしてそれは下の谷から遠く離れています
It takes about 40 minutes to an hour to climb up.
登るのに40分から1時間ほどかかります。
Some villages take two hours to go up
登るのに2時間かかる村もある
This is where you see them, this is a black tiger
これが彼らを見るところです、これはブラックタイガーです
Not that Oxtail Village
オックステール村ではありません
During Chinese New Year, this is the beginning of the year and they have a ceremony
中国の旧正月には、これが年の始まりであり、儀式が行われます。
inside a religious ceremony
宗教儀式の中で
They're young and old with guns
彼らは老いも若きも銃を持っている
Shooting in the air, around a disused field next to the village
村の隣の使われなくなった畑の周りで空中撮影
walk around
歩き回る
In fact, they are all expressing
実際、彼らはすべて表現しています
We are very determined to protect our Siyuan border
私たちは思源の国境を守ることに強い決意を持っています
This girl wears the same clothes
この女の子は同じ服を着ています
now everyone will pay attention
今なら誰もが注目するだろう
Everywhere these girls dress alike
どこに行っても、この女の子たちは似たような服装をしている
then just say
それならただ言ってください
This is the national costume tradition of our gun clan
これは私たちのガン一族の民族衣装の伝統です
But for the locals
でも地元の人にとっては
That's not it, similarity doesn't matter
そうじゃない、類似性は関係ない
The important thing is the difference between his clothing and that of the village next to him
重要なのは彼の服装と近くの村の服装の違いです
Even a small distinction is very important to them
たとえ小さな違いであっても、彼らにとっては非常に重要です
because in this place
なぜならこの場所で
Resource competition and differentiation are important
資源競争と差別化が重要
so this is
それでこれは
back to my field work
畑仕事に戻ります
Xiaoxinge Aiqi Village, where I live the most
私が最もよく住んでいる小新閣愛七村
You see, this village is different from the one before
ほら、この村は前とは違うんだよ
it is scattered
散らばっている
i know them well
私は彼らをよく知っています
so i joke with them sometimes
だから私は時々彼らと冗談を言います
once i said
一度私が言った
You are so small, why did your house fall apart?
あなたはとても小さいのに、なぜ家が壊れたのですか？
not get together like you
あなたのように集まらないでください
they said yes
彼らはそうだと言った
we never noticed this
私たちはこれに気付かなかった
make sense
わかる
I said because you are robbing people
あなたが人から物を奪っているからと言ったのです
you were not robbed
あなたは盗まれませんでした
They used to be very upstream
昔はかなり上流にあったんだよ
famous savage
有名な野蛮人
Local within an identity system
アイデンティティ システム内のローカル
very interesting
とても興味深い
people from every region
あらゆる地域から来た人々
In fact, what I call a region is not a very big one.
実際、私がエリアと呼んでいるのは、それほど大きなエリアではありません。
It's just a small ditch or a section of a small ditch.
それは単なる小さな溝、または小さな溝の一部です。
The people over there may be just a few children
あそこにいる人たちはほんの数人の子供たちかもしれない
They call themselves Erma
彼らは自分たちをエルマと呼びます
People in the upper reaches are called barbarians
上流の人々は野蛮人と呼ばれます
Then the people downstream are those cunning Han Chinese
そうすると下流にいるのは狡猾な漢民族だ
But the people from that village called Manzi
しかし、その村の人々はマンジと呼ばれました
He also calls himself a horse
彼は自分自身を馬とも呼んでいます
Then he called the people below are Han Chinese
それから彼は下の人々を漢民族だと呼びました
On the contrary, you think others are barbarians
それどころか、あなたは他人を野蛮人だと思っています
Others think you are Han Chinese
他の人はあなたを漢民族だと思っています
He thinks the barbarian is on the root
彼は野蛮人が根にあると考えている
So this is a situation of ethnic identity in the local area
これが地元地域における民族アイデンティティの状況です
So it's New Year's Eve
ということで大晦日です
their wedding ceremony
彼らの結婚式
This is also Xiaoxingou Aiqi Village
ここも小興溝愛奇村です
it's winter
冬です
outside their house
彼らの家の外で
Pile up a lot of firewood
薪をたくさん積み上げます
inside the house
家の中
There are some pig signs hanging on the roof beams
屋根の梁に豚の看板がいくつかぶら下がっています
for them
彼らのために
This is the greatest safety in life
これが人生における最大の安全です
Maximum protection
最大限の保護
So we take a look at the history of what they believe
そこで彼らが信じてきたことの歴史を見てみましょう
This is what the people in the ditch in Egypt said
エジプトの溝にいた人々はこう言った
This is what I use to record and divide it into text
これは私が記録してテキストに分割するために使用するものです
He said that the first time there was no one
初めて誰もいなかったと彼は言いました
three brothers big brother is a woman
三兄弟兄貴は女です
brother here
ここの兄弟
Another one invited a brother to the Iraqi team
別の人は兄弟をイラクチームに招待しました
My brother said that I can bask in the sun when I live here
兄は、ここに住めば日光浴ができると言った
So the sun shines early for the three teams
ということで、3チームの日差しが早くなりました
invite brother a little scared
少し怖いお兄さんを招待します
The second brother said that if you die, you will be buried in my second team.
次兄は、もしあなたが死んだら、私の二番目のチームに埋葬されると言った。
So a team of dead people are brought here to be buried
それで、死んだ人々のチームが埋葬のためにここに運ばれます
it's such a simple history
それはとても単純な歴史です
that means the people of this place
それはこの場所の人々を意味します
The relationship between the three in sub
サブの三人の関係
Also this is what another guy told me
また、これは他の男性が私に言ったことです
He said that the seven brothers from the top
彼は上から7人の兄弟だと言いました。
Some of the seven brothers are in the big ear
7人の兄弟のうちの何人かは大きな耳を持っています
some in pigs ears
豚の耳の一部
That's how those wolves fucked your dad
そうやってオオカミたちは君のお父さんを犯したんだ
they are here
彼らはここにいます
What dynasty was fanned
どの王朝が煽られたのか
run here
ここに走ってください
It turns out that there is no one here
ここには誰もいないことが判明しました
Here are the seven brothers
こちらが七人兄弟です
You see he later said only three brothers came
後で彼は3人の兄弟だけが来たと言ったのがわかりますか
Four more brothers are out there
あと4人兄弟がいる
The seven big ears Niba
七つの大きな耳ニバ
This is how people are divided
こうやって人は分かれていくんだな
So this one is different from the one just now
つまり、これは今のものとは異なります
story told
語られた物語
That is to say, the three brothers
つまり三兄弟
It turned out to be three of the seven brothers
7人兄弟のうちの3人だったことが判明
This is another record
これは別の記録です
This man also told me
この人も言ってた
he became nine
彼は9歳になった
He said nine brothers came
彼は9人の兄弟が来たと言った
nine brothers stand there
9人の兄弟がそこに立っています
Three brothers started a fire in this ditch
3 人の兄弟がこの溝で火を起こしました
two brothers over there
そこにいる二人の兄弟
So there's an interesting dictation from him later on.
それで、後で彼から興味深い口述があります。
i read it out
私はそれを読み上げました
He said the nine brothers were Huang Cao
九兄弟は黄操だと言っていた
he ask me
彼は私に尋ねます
Qin Dynasty or Huang Cao
秦王朝または黄操
Qin Dynasty three people eight million
秦王朝三人八百万
Huang Cao three people eight million
黄操三名八百万
I said whatever
何でも言いました
he can't escape
彼は逃げられない
here it is
ここにあります
A family of little brothers came here
小さな兄弟の家族がここに来ました
We know that Qin Dynasty and Huang Cao
私たちは秦王朝と黄操を知っています。
one is the people
一つは人々です
And the times are far behind
そして時代ははるかに遅れています
What does this mean?
これは何を意味するのでしょうか？
That time means nothing to them.
その時間は彼らにとって何の意味も持たない
Their history is a past combined with the present
彼らの歴史は過去と現在が組み合わさったものです
In the past few brothers came here
過去に何人かの兄弟がここに来ました
what are we now
私たちは今何ですか
This is a very special kind of history
これは非常に特殊な歴史です
so everyone see
だからみんな見て
I can simplify the first few to this
最初のいくつかをこれに単純化できます
if you want to explain this side
この面を説明したい場合は
The origin of the three Zai Ziren
三才子連の由来
You said once upon a time three brothers came here
昔、三人の兄弟がここに来たって言ってたね
then go to a place alone
それから一人でどこかへ行く
And then you have to explain where this large range of people comes from?
そして、この幅広い人々がどこから来たのかを説明する必要がありますか?
You say that once upon a time seven brothers came here
昔々、7人の兄弟がここに来たと君は言う
Then what about everyone?
それでは皆さんはどうでしょうか？
stand alone in one place
一か所に一人で立つ
and then a wider range
それからさらに広い範囲
This is if you go to Jiuzhaigou to play
九寨溝に遊びに行くならこれ
take off when the plane lands
飛行機が着陸したら離陸する
did you see a big mountain
大きな山を見ましたか
That's called Snowberg Peak
それはスノーバーグピークと呼ばれています
If you ask him, he said that the top mountain of Snow Castle
聞けばスノーキャッスルピークマウンテンだそうです。
that plugged in
差し込まれたもの
Where did all the people come from?
みんなどこから来たの？
He will tell you another
彼は別のことを教えてくれるでしょう
seven brothers story
七人兄弟の物語
That is to say, how can these people believe
つまり、どうしてこの人たちは信じられるのかというと、
Such a strange history, right?
なんとも奇妙な歴史ですよね？
ok i tell you
わかりました、言います
to tell everyone is to say
みんなに言うことは言うことだ
Why do they believe this history
なぜ彼らはこの歴史を信じるのか
Egyptian village has three children
エジプトの村には3人の子供がいる
one pair two pair three pair
1 ペア 2 ペア 3 ペア
There are more than fifty households
50世帯以上あります
just a small child
ただの小さな子供
One-to-two couples in Yingsan-myeon
営山面の1～2組のカップル
That's what I just said
それが私が今言ったことです
Who said he was a little scared when he died?
死ぬときは少し怖かったと誰が言いましたか？
He said his brother said
弟がこう言ったそうです
Then you die and bury me here
それからあなたは死んで私をここに埋めてください
In fact, the reaction is that these two sons
実際、この二人の息子の反応は、
close relationship
親密な関係
Three pairs in Yangshan-myeon
梁山面の3組
Yangshan noodles usually we say
よく言う楊山麺
This is what the sun shines early in the morning
これは早朝の太陽の輝きです
So production is better
だから生産性は向上する
Usually more people
通常人比較多
so they just
それで彼らはただ
the story just now
今の話
History says that he was the big brother
歴史によれば彼は兄貴だった
admit he's the big brother
彼が兄であることを認める
But it's a bit derogatory to him
でもそれは彼にとって少し軽蔑的だ
Said big brother because it is a neck
お兄さんがネックだからって言った
so we let him
それで私たちは彼に任せました
so in this place
だからこの場所で
The homes and houses of coal households are all located on the foundation of a specific land god
石炭世帯の家や家はすべて特定の土地神の基礎の上にあります
The name of the land god is also the name of the family
土地神の名前は家族の名前でもある
and very consciously
そして非常に意識的に
No land God can't build a house
神が家を建てられない土地はない
So what is the effect of everyone being so smart?
それでは、誰もが非常に賢くなるとどのような影響があるのでしょうか?
in this ravine
この渓谷で
If there are 30 households, there will always be 30 households
30世帯あれば常に30世帯あります。
Forever 50 households
永遠に50世帯
If there are 50 land gods, there will always be 50 households
土地神が50人いれば必ず50世帯ある
Another effect is
もう一つの効果は、
I'm for relatives, it's actually a spatial relationship
私は親戚のためです、それは実際には空間的な関係です
Because if you move to another
だって他に移ったら
For example, a place is vacant
たとえば、場所が空いている
There is a father who has many sons
たくさんの息子を持つ父親がいる
He can't help living at home is difficult
彼は家で暮らすのが難しくて仕方ない
He can get the consent of other people in Murakami
村上で他人の同意を得ることができる
Said my son was going to take that place
私の息子がその場所を引き受けると言いました
build a house over there
あそこに家を建てて
If everyone in the village agrees
村全員が同意すれば
Then his son will set up a household there
それから彼の息子はそこに家庭を築くでしょう
Then the father and the son will become
そうすれば父と子はこうなるだろう
into a different family
別の家族に
because of that son
あの息子のせいで
he is the inherited family
彼は相続された家族です
The wound of the land god
地盤神的傷
so think about it
だからそれについて考えてください
What does it mean to live in the historical construction
歴史的建造物に住むとはどういう意味ですか
In social reality
社会現実において
That is to say, today a person of the second race
つまり今日は第二種族の人
he went hunting
彼は狩りに行きました
he chased a camphor
彼は樟脳を追いかけた
one way
一方通行
When chasing to the edge of the clan's territory
一族の領土の端まで追いかけるとき
he stopped suddenly
彼は突然立ち止まった
in his heart
彼の心の中で
because that history told him
その歴史が彼に語ったからだ
This is not the land of our ancestors
ここは私たちの先祖の土地ではありません
And their ancestors were brothers to mine
そして彼らの先祖は私の兄弟でした
so if today i
それで、もし今日私が
words that cross the line
一線を越えた言葉
it will break the brotherhood
それは兄弟関係を壊すことになる
so he stopped
それで彼はやめた
so think about it
だからそれについて考えてください
people live in this history
人はこの歴史の中で生きている
Your actions and actions all prove this history
あなたの行動と行動はすべてこの歴史を証明しています
so maybe this time
だから今度は多分
another one
もう一つ
people of that clan
その一族の人々
Will watch super super super
超超超見るよ
not crossing the line
一線を越えていない
Then he sees you cross the line
それから彼はあなたが一線を越えているのを見ます
good
良い
You are still my good brother
あなたは今でも私の良い兄弟です
What if at this time
この時だったらどうしよう
They heard a whistling in the distance
彼らは遠くで口笛を聞いた
he knows
彼は知っている
there is a side
側面があります
people with big ear ditches maybe
耳溝が大きい人かもしれない
come over here to hunt frog waist
カエルの腰を狩りにここに来てください
and then everyone
それからみんな
I have to go there to drive people away
私はそこに行って人々を追い払わなければなりません
why
なぜ
because history tells them
歴史が物語っているから
Our ancestors were three brothers
私たちの祖先は三人兄弟でした
brothers are cooperative
兄弟は協力的です
so what
だから何
Cooperation distinguishes confrontation
協力は対立を区別する
in this history
この歴史の中で
a very important narrative symbol
非常に重要な物語の象徴
is brother
兄弟です
his three metaphors
彼の3つの比喩
it's brother
それは兄弟です
is cooperative
協力的です
Because brothers are born of the same father
兄弟は同じ父親から生まれたから
and what about brother
そして兄弟はどうですか
It's another brother's name
もう一人の兄弟の名前です
Brothers of all kinds
いろんな種類の兄弟たち
and brother
そして兄弟
There will always be some small contradictions
小さな矛盾は必ずある
forever in this little struggle
この小さな戦いで永遠に
So people live in historically constructed
人々は歴史的に構築された場所に住んでいます
this social phenomenon
この社会現象
And then the social reality is so real
そして社会的現実は非常に現実的です
Because every action of yours is confirming this history
あなたのあらゆる行動がこの歴史を裏付けるものだから
People naturally believe and care about this history
人々は自然にこの歴史を信じ、関心を持ちます
So in this place apart from the history
だから歴史から離れたこの場所で
wait a minute if you have time you can talk
時間があれば話せますのでちょっと待ってください
their Trinity disc belief
彼らのトリニティディスク信仰
all guide and tell them what to do
全員がガイドし、何をすべきかを指示します
A person's actions follow these
人の行動はこれに従う
What we call history and culture and religion
私たちが歴史、文化、宗教と呼ぶもの
So this history is actually the same as our history
つまり、この歴史は私たちの歴史と同じなのです
seems to have a lot of details
たくさんの詳細があるようです
There are also some small details in their history.
彼らの歴史にはいくつかの小さな詳細があります
These details also differentiate this group of people
これらの詳細もこのグループの人々を区別します
This detail is sometimes too simple to tell.
この詳細は、単純すぎて伝えることができない場合があります。
It is often said that when the three brothers separated
よく言われるのは、三兄弟が別れたとき、
they kill a cow
彼らは牛を殺します
One for the head, one for the tail and one for the body
1 つは頭用、1 つは尻尾用、もう 1 つは体用
or when three brothers separated
あるいは三人の兄弟が別れたとき
One to one who seems like they say metal
メタルって言いそうなマンツーマン
a man made of gold
金でできた男
One is the silver man
一人は銀の男です
Iron Man
鉄人
and then something like this
それからこのようなもの
it's that simple
それはとても簡単です
So they usually yell and yell
だから彼らはたいてい大声で叫んでる
Like the Yonghegou side
雍和溝側のように
Who is the descendant of Niu Pizi?
牛皮子の子孫は誰ですか?
who is the offspring of oxtail
オックステールの子孫は誰ですか
Of course, a cowhide oxtail
もちろん牛革オックステールです
it must be a comparison
それは比較に違いない
The relatively weaker this, this, and this Zaizi
相対的に弱いこれとこれとこのザイジ
What about Beichuan Inner and Outer Ditch?
北川の内溝と外溝はどうですか？
This place is more Chinese
この場所はもっと中国的です
So you see they have Chinese surnames
つまり、彼らは中国人の姓を持っていることがわかります
Zhang exiled three surnames to Xiaoba
張氏は三つの姓を暁巴氏に追放した。
come three brothers
三人兄弟が来ます
So it is impossible for the three brothers to intermarry
つまり、三兄弟が結婚することは不可能である
So I changed my last name
それで苗字を変えました
Then they said that a person stood in a ditch
それから彼らは人が溝に立っていると言いました
One is Sanshulin
一つはサンシュリンです
That's Liu's
それはリューさんです
The other is the inner and outer grooves
もう一つは内溝と外溝です
It was a farm
農場でした
In fact, there is a big controversy
実は大きな論争が起きているんです
Now say it's Wang's
さあ、ワンさんのものだと言ってください
So some oral histories like this
このようなオーラルヒストリーもあります
Actually very inspiring to me
実は私にとってとても刺激的なのです
Indicates that history is often changed in such disputes
このような紛争では歴史がしばしば変わることを示しています
So the belief in the three gods in the ditch of Egypt is the same
つまり、エジプトの溝の三神への信仰は同じです
Each of the three carriers has its own territory
3 つの航空会社にはそれぞれ独自の領土があります
So they banded together to protect their common turf
そこで彼らは共通の縄張りを守るために団結した
So the three gods are also used to emphasize this kind of human ecology
三神はこうした人間の生態を強調するためにも使われているのですね。
Simply put, each carrier has its own three gods
簡単に言えば、各航空会社には独自の 3 つの神がいます。
Then combine if the three carriers have a groove
3 つのキャリアに溝がある場合は結合します
The three of them together have a bigger three gods
三人合わせてさらに大きな三神がいる
So the biggest three gods in this place are Coronado
つまり、この場所の最大の三神はコロナドです
This is the symbol of the three gods
これは三神の象徴です
a sign on the hill
丘の上の標識
So when I run up the hills with these friends who live with guns
だから銃を持って暮らす友人たちと丘を駆け上がるとき
When you come across a sign like this
こんな看板を見つけたら
we're going to walk around
私たちは歩き回ります
less numbers plugged in to show worship
崇拝を示すために接続される数字が少なくなる
This means that
この意味は
I respect other people's territory boundaries
私は他人の領域の境界を尊重します
The location of the three gods is usually the boundary of the territory
三神の位置は通常、領土の境界である
ok let's see now
さて、それでは見てみましょう
Jialong Tibetan
嘉隆チベット語
what they call history
彼らが歴史と呼ぶもの
So let me briefly introduce
それでは簡単にご紹介させていただきます
Everyone knows the location
場所はみんな知ってるよ
its environment of production
その生産環境
Very similar to the neighbor's gun family
近所の銃一家によく似ている
It also has a similar tritheistic belief
同様の三神教の信念もある
That is to say, it is the same here
つまりここも同じ
that is
あれは
As long as there is faith in the three gods
三神への信仰がある限り
Everyone pays great attention to the land
誰もが土地に細心の注意を払っています
Then also have this
じゃあこれもどうぞ
No house can be built where there is no site god
敷地の神のいないところに家は建てられない
this custom
この習慣
But in the homes of ordinary people here
でもここの普通の人たちの家では
I can not find
をみつけられない
I can't interview people like this
こんな人にはインタビューできない
History of the Dixiong's Ancestors
地雄族の祖先の歴史
Then this kind of history only exists in the beliefs of the various Tushi families in the past
それでは、この種の歴史は過去のさまざまなトゥシ家の信仰の中にのみ存在します。
Sorry, I'm here to explain to you
申し訳ありませんが、説明するためにここに来ました
I forgot to say first
最初に言うのを忘れていました
In fact, the situation I am talking about
実際、私が話している状況は、
mostly before the 1950s
ほとんどが1950年代以前
At most, this situation lasted until 1960 and 70
この状況はせいぜい 1960 年から 1970 年まで続いた
Later, because after the so-called liberation of mainland China
その後、いわゆる中国本土の解放後
there is a big change
大きな変化があります
So this is what it used to be
それで、これは前に起こったことです
In the past, this place was governed by various chieftains
かつて、この場所はさまざまな族長によって統治されていました。
They all usually refer to people from all over the world by the name of Tusi
彼らは通常、世界中の人々をトゥシという名前で指します。
Such as this Badi, Bawang, Zaku, Droth family
このバディ、バワン、ザク、ドロスファミリーなど
Then each chieftain led probably a dozen to dozens of villages
その後、各族長はおそらく十数から数十の村を率いました。
and very important
そしてとても重要な
They are different from Gunru
グンルとは違うんだよ
they are very religious
彼らはとても宗教的です
Followers of Tibetan Buddhism
チベット仏教の信者
You see, the river next to it is the Dadu River
ほら、その隣の川は大肚江です
this is a village
ここは村です
This village came out of this ravine
この村はこの渓谷から出てきた
This little bit of alluvial soil is filled and cultivated here
このわずかな沖積土が埋め立てられ、ここで栽培されています。
So the location of this village
さて、この村の場所は
it's about the place
それは場所のことです
This is not the same as the gun bamboo
これは鉄砲竹とは違います
Qiangzhu would never dare to build a village so close to the river
強主は川の近くに村を建てる勇気はないだろう
On the one hand, I am afraid of flooding, on the other hand, I am also afraid of being forced
洪水が怖い一方で、強制被害も怖い
This is the village of Merlo
ここはメルロ村です
This is one of my field points
これは私のフィールドポイントの1つです
Wait a minute, everyone can see
ちょっと待ってください、誰でも見ることができます
this is also a
これもまた
The house and the form of the settlement are also a sign
家も集落の形も記号
wait a minute you look at this and that
ちょっと待って、あれやこれや見てください
Wait a minute I'm showing you this
ちょっと待ってください、これをお見せします
The House of Liang Fan Yi Family
リャン・ファンイー家の家
very different
とても違う
Simply put, you can see that this house is very delicate
簡単に言えば、この家は非常に繊細であることがわかります
Because its house is built on the site rope
敷地のロープの上に家が建っているので
So once you cover it and live there, it will last a long time.
そのため、一度カバーをして住めば長く使えます。
not easy to move
動きにくい
So their house is very particular
彼らの家は非常に特殊です
This is also the year when I went to take pictures for their wedding
今年は結婚式の写真を撮りに行った年でもあります
so this kind of wedding
だからこういう結婚式
This is called Qilu Village
ここは斉魯村と呼ばれています
Go to Morle Village and bring this girl back
モール村に行ってこの娘を連れ戻してください
This kind of wedding is where the whole village attends
この種の結婚式は村全体が出席するものです
The whole village will stay in Moerle Village for one night
村全員がメール村に一晩滞在します
The next day the girl bid farewell to the elder
次の日、少女は長老に別れを告げた。
Then go to her husband's village
それから夫の村に行きます
So this place is also famous as the Valley of Beauty
この場所は美の谷としても有名です
Look at this, it's really beautiful
これを見てください、本当に美しいです
But this actually shows another
しかし、これは実際には別のことを示しています
Phenomena unrelated to my research
私の研究とは関係のない現象
I just told you
私はちょうどあなたに言いました
Diversity can be found here in every discipline
多様性はあらゆる分野で見られます
This is one of the genetic diversity
これも遺伝的多様性の一つです
That is to say, some genes happen to be concentrated in this place
つまり、ある遺伝子がたまたまこの場所に集中しているということです。
Let me tell you this village is called Badi Village
これは、この村がこのバディ村と呼ばれていることを示しています
There are more than a dozen villages here in Badi
ここバディには十数の村があります
people are beautiful
人々は美しいです
There is also a Meinan Valley
名南渓谷もあります
If you are interested, you can ask me
興味があれば聞いてみてください
It's even weirder if you look at the history here.
ここの歴史を見るとさらに奇妙です。
But this history is from the 1930s to the turn of the 40s when
しかし、この歴史は 1930 年代から 40 年代の変わり目までのものです。
An early anthropologist Mr. Ma Changshou
初期の人類学者馬長寿氏
he is collected
彼は集められている
He said that the lion of the barren valley has a giant bird to meet the poor
彼は、不毛の谷のライオンは貧しい人々を迎えるために巨大な鳥を持っていると言った
born in poor cloth
貧しい生地で生まれた
This is the name of the virtue of poor cloth
これは貧しい布の美徳の名前です
He is called Lord of the Poor Birds
彼は貧しい鳥の主と呼ばれています
the bird laid five eggs
鳥は5個の卵を産みました
One red one green one white one black one flower
赤 1 緑 1 白 1 黒 1 花
A person came out of the flower egg
花の卵から人が出てきた
Bear hand life, eye descendants
熊手人生 眼神子孫
Taining
タイニン
This Taining is Bamei
この泰寧はバメイです
just when he was near a
ちょうど彼が近くにいたとき
A small center of a Tibetan Buddhist
チベット仏教の小さなセンター
lead to the bottom
一番下に戻る
Then on the eight bottom side
続いて8番下側
He gave birth to two brothers
彼は二人の兄弟を産んだ
It's just these two people who will become apprentices with all kinds of prosperity
この二人だけで色々な繁栄が見習いになります
take a look
みんなを見て
There is an extra symbol of this poor bird on it
このかわいそうな鳥の追加のシンボルがあります
right
右
This is what is said in Tibetan Buddhism
チベット仏教ではこう言われています
a garuda
一個Garuda
Garuda
ガルーダ
Read this story below
このストーリーを以下で読んでください
still a brother story at the end
最後はまだ兄弟の物語
use a brother story
兄弟の話を使う
To show the ancestral relationship of the two apprentices
二人の弟子の先祖関係を示すため
This is also collected by Mr. Ma Changshou
こちらも馬長寿氏が収集したもの
Ge Se Zhan Tushi's ancestors in his family
Ge Se Zhan Tushi の家族の先祖
He said that our ancestors were brought from the poor Ministry of 39
彼は、私たちの祖先は39の貧しい省から連れてこられたと言いました。
The poor actually refers to
貧乏人というのは実際に言うと、
Just like Lhasa
ラサみたいに
He said that this has been here for three, four or five generations.
ここは3、4、5世代にわたってここにあると彼は言いました。
When I came here, there were four brothers
私がここに来たとき、4人の兄弟がいました
You see the same poor bird symbol
同じ哀れな鳥のシンボルが見えます
Then there are four brothers
それから兄弟は４人です
another brother story
もう一つの兄弟の話
So this is the ancestor of another Zhuoshijia toast
つまり、これは別の卓世家トーストの祖先です
also the same
また同じです
Every one of these toasts tells a story about their ancestors
これらの乾杯のそれぞれが先祖についての物語を語ります
It's all like a pattern
それはすべてパターンのようなものです
follow this pattern
このパターンに従ってください
so why do they care about history like this
ではなぜ彼らはこのように歴史を気にするのでしょうか
very simple
とてもシンプルな
It's the toast family
トーストファミリーです
their divinity and ruling authority
彼らの神性と支配的権威
It is from this history
こういう歴史からです
In addition, the relationship between the toast and the adjacent toast
また、トーストと隣接するトーストとの関係
It is shown in the brother's story below
それは以下の兄弟の話に示されています
he thinks more
彼はもっと考えます
The more he thinks that toast and I are brothers
トーストと私が兄弟だと思えば思うほど
means
意味
friend and foe
友人と敵
It's the closer the relationship
そのほうが関係が近くなります
The most I do in the field is to look at the bottom and the bottom
私がフィールドでやっているのは、底と底を見ることだけです
These two places are
この２か所は、
that's what the relationship is like
それが関係のようなものです
And the language of the two places is completely different
そして二つの場所の言語は全く異なります
They know each other's language is full of curse words
彼らはお互いの言葉が罵り合いであることを知っている
They've heard each other talk since they were kids
彼らは子供の頃からお互いの話を聞いていた
He came back and asked his parents
彼は戻ってきて両親に尋ねました
The people on the other side of the river called me or something
川の向こう側の人々が私に電話をかけてきたとかなんとか
what is that
それは何ですか
So all he learns is swearing
だから彼が学ぶのは悪口だけだ
so there is
だからあるよ
It is the core area of local Tibetan Buddhism
地元チベット仏教の中核地域です
It native and Tibetan Buddha
土着のチベット仏陀
It is to admit that one is a Tibetan Buddhist
自分がチベット仏教徒であることを認めることです
we are the edge
私たちはエッジです
all core
すべてのコア
So I also collected here
そこで私もここに集めました
very interesting
とても興味深い
There is a special family called the Vastus
ヴァストゥスと呼ばれる特別な家族がいます
At the exact epicenter of the 2008 Great Western Sichuan Earthquake
2008 年の四川省西部大地震の震源地に位置
right here
ここにあります
I have collected and seen three versions here
ここで3つのバージョンを集めて見ました
Three brothers in the same family
同じ家族の 3 人の兄弟
Actually told the history of three different pairs of families
3組の異なる家族の歴史を実際に語った
The first one is what the family tree of Tusi said
最初のものはトゥシの家系図が言ったことです
It's mainly about one of their ancestors
それは主に彼らの先祖の一人についてです
be a hero
ヒーローになる
From Ushizang is from Lhasa
牛蔵出身はラサ出身
Then come to replace China's poverty
そして中国の貧困に取って代わる存在となる
So China gave him Xuanwei envoy
そこで中国は彼に宣為使節を与えた
Then just manage the natives here
それならここの原住民を管理するだけです
The story is that the chieftain's younger brother
物語は、族長の弟です。
Usually the chieftain's younger brother is the main local lama
通常、首長の弟が地元の主要なラマ僧である
This lama told the story of their family
このラマ僧は家族の話をしました
You see, it's the same as the previous one again
ほら、また前のものと同じです
The big bird in the sky laid a few more eggs
空の大きな鳥はさらにいくつかの卵を産みました
Then how does this egg go?
では、この卵はどうなるでしょうか？
which toast
どの乾杯
This is another brother of a chieftain
これは族長のもう一人の兄弟です
This brother, he talked about it again and again.
この兄弟は、何度も何度もそのことについて話しました。
It is said that Henan people have a Three Kingdoms
河南人には三国志があると言われています
what brought four people
何が4人を連れてきたのか
A son immigrated to Sichuan
息子が四川省に移住
one to one
一対一
One to Jintang Peng Xian generation
金唐彭賢世代までの1人
there is one more here
ここにもう一つあります
there's one more back
後ろにもう1人いる
Returning to Yuanji means returning to Henan
元吉に帰るということは河南に帰るということだ
So you see this becomes a bro story again
これがまた兄弟の物語になるのがわかりますか
right
右
what's going on
どうしたの？
Actually
実際
Because of this I feel that this history
だからこそ、この歴史は
really very strange
本当にとても奇妙な
that's what i'm talking about
それは私が話しているものです
they happen to be caught in
彼らはたまたま巻き込まれる
Between the two forces of Han and Tibetan
漢民族とチベット民族の二つの勢力の間
So he is in the same family
つまり彼は同じ家族なのです
Where are the three brothers?
三兄弟はどこですか？
They care about different histories
彼らはさまざまな歴史を気にしています
that big brother is toast
あの兄貴は乾杯だ
Of course he cares about the first version
もちろん彼は最初のバージョンを気にしています
Because that can prove his identity as a toast
それが乾杯として身分を証明できるから
right
右
The second brother is a lama
次兄はラマ僧です
He believes in the kind of divinity
彼は一種の神性を信じている
he and each toast
彼とそれぞれの乾杯
family relationship
家族関係
this old
この古い
where is this toast
このトーストはどこですか
He's talking about a local culture
彼は地元の文化について話しています
special culture
特別な文化
How do you think about history?
歴史についてどう思いますか？
all brothers
兄弟です
At first it was a few brothers
最初は数人の兄弟でした
good
良い
Finally, I want to talk about this Liangshan survivor
最後に、この涼山の生存者について話したいと思います。
look
見て
His population is different from before
彼の人口は以前とは異なります
Of course, the Liangshan area is relatively large
もちろん涼山エリアは比較的広いです
bigger than the previous ones
以前のものより大きい
But more people
でももっと人が
23.06 million
2,306万
In addition to the Jiaotong University basin,
交通大学流域に加えて、
His environment is similar to that of the Sichuan-Tibetan Qiang people
彼の環境は四川チベットのチャン族と似ています
He is a part-time farmer and logger
他農木兼營
These are similar to the Tibetan accent
これらはチベットのアクセントに似ています
But the biggest difference is his sociality
しかし、最大の違いは彼の社交性です
his this
彼のこれ
he
他
Let me just say it here
ここで一つだけ言わせてください
He doesn't have the belief in the three gods of the Tibetan people
彼はチベット民族の三神に対する信仰を持っていない
But he has a wealth of skill combined with blood
しかし彼は血と合わせた豊富なスキルを持っています
This is something Tibetans don't have
これはチベット人にはないものです
So everyone, think about Tibetan accents
だから皆さん、チベットのアクセントについて考えてください
the kind of history we just talked about
私たちが今話したような歴史
There is only one past combined with the present
現在と合わせた過去は一つだけ
if the family history
家族歴の場合
Almost only three generations at most
せいぜい3世代くらいしかない
I don't remember any further
それ以上は覚えていない
Then the structure of their house is very simple
彼らの家の構造は非常に単純です
And do not pay attention to the site
そして、サイトに注意を払わないでください
They don't even like to build houses on old machines
彼らは古い機械で家を建てることさえ好まない
They love to move around
彼らは動き回るのが大好きです
and very important
そしてとても重要な
He has rulers and ruled
彼には支配者がいて統治している
A Consecutive Total Information Society
続く総合情報化社会
So of course this is over
だからもちろんこれで終わり
But his traces are still there
しかし彼の痕跡はまだ残っている
They are divided into rulers are black chairs
彼らは定規に分かれており、黒い椅子です
The white chair is the subordinate farmer
白い椅子は従属農家です
Then there are two other classes behind are slaves
次に、後ろに他の 2 つのクラスがあり、それらは奴隷です
Both the black chair and the white chair have family property
黒い椅子も白い椅子も家族の所有物です
Everyone belongs to his family property
誰もが自分の家族の財産に属しています
Concentration of black chair family property residence
黒椅子家財邸の集中
The white chair family property is because of him
ホワイトチェア家の財産は彼のおかげです
it belongs to each black chair
それはそれぞれの黒い椅子に属します
so they are difficult to unite
だから彼らは団結するのが難しい
this is how it used to be
かつてはこうだった
look at this house
この家を見てください
this house is abandoned
この家は放棄されています
So their houses are built very simply
彼らの家はとてもシンプルに建てられています
If you want to move, just throw it away.
移動したい場合は、捨ててください。
Look here and that too
こっちもこっちも見てね
this is the house over there
これがあそこの家です
the village
村落
in this village
この村で
everywhere you can see
どこにでも見える
These formerly abandoned houses
かつては廃墟となったこれらの家々
Because they don't like building on old foundations
彼らは古い基盤の上に建物を建てることを好まないからです
This may also be obsolete
これも廃盤かも知れません
This is where people live
ここは人々が住んでいる場所です
The house is very
家はとても
compared to the front
正面と比べて
very simple
とてもシンプルな
These two are white chairs
この 2 つは白い椅子です
this is the black chair
これは黒い椅子です
this is his grandmother
これは彼の祖母です
let's visit him
彼を訪ねてみましょう
Then
それから
I tell a few stories about this little boy
この小さな男の子についていくつかの話をします
that
それか
This kind of historical memory in their home can best illustrate
彼らの家におけるこの種の歴史的記憶が最もよく説明できます。
this kind of
このたぐいの
Because when he took me around to visit
なぜなら、彼が私を訪問に連れて行ってくれたとき、
Often I hear someone ask him
誰かが彼に尋ねるのをよく聞きます
Are you the kid who burned down the house?
あなたは家を燃やした子供ですか？
I listened to it a few times and came back one night when we were chatting
何度か聞いて、ある夜おしゃべりしているときに戻ってきました
I'll just say what great things you did as a kid
あなたが子供の頃にどんな素晴らしいことをしたのかだけを話します
people remember you
人々はあなたのことを覚えています
he was very embarrassed
彼はとても恥ずかしがっていた
Said I was playing with fire in the back of the house once when my dad called me
お父さんに叱られたとき、家の裏で火遊びしてたって言ってたよ
Burn the whole village in half
村全体の半分を焼き払う
Say this, this, this, his father, this
こう言ってください、これを言ってください、彼のお父さん、これを言ってください
The sheep are all sold and there is nothing to do with them
羊はすべて売れてしまったので、彼らと付き合うために私にできることは何もありません
So let's take him and everyone to think about this scene that looks very touching.
それでは、彼とみんなで、とても感動的に見えるこのシーンについて考えてみましょう。
A father with a six-year-old child
6歳の子供を持つ父親
Mountains everywhere in Liangshan Prefecture began to be called home
涼山県のいたるところの山々が故郷と呼ばれるようになりました
Everyone knows that the name of this family is to remember which family I belong to
この家族の名前は、私がどの家族に属しているかを覚えておくためのものであることは誰もが知っています
what is our family history
私たちの家族の歴史は何ですか
You can read each other
お互いに読み合えるよ
You'll know how close you are to me
あなたがどれだけ私に近いかわかるでしょう
Nearly pay 100 yuan
100元近く払う
20 yuan for a little farther
少し遠くまで20元
probably like this
おそらくこんな感じ
Said it took more than half a year
半年以上かかったって言ってた
Lost all others
他はすべて失った
this is for me
これは私のためにあります
that is to say I heard him say
つまり、私は彼がこう言うのを聞いたのです
on the one hand very touched
一方でとても感動した
On the one hand it is a very special experience
一方で、それは非常に特別な経験です
why?
なぜ？
in Tibetan area
チベット地域で
there will never be such a thing
そんなことは決してないだろう
Because it's common for houses to burn down here
ここでは家が全焼することがよくあるから
But except for the native people in the Tibetan area
ただし、チベット地域の先住民族を除く。
listen to you build the house
家を建てるのを聞いてください
How can you possibly seek help from outsiders?
どうして外部から誰かに助けを求めることができるでしょうか？
This is where the survivors are very powerful in the local area.
ここは地元で生存者が非常に力を持っている場所です
Also from another point of view
また別の観点から
In the past, it was also a place where the survivors were considered very barbaric.
過去には、ここは生存者が非常に野蛮だと考えられていた場所でもありました。
Why?
なぜ？
The bereaved are different from the Tibetan
遺族はチベット人とは違う
They dare to go out to open up wasteland and conquer the world
彼らはあえて荒地を開拓し、世界を征服しようとします。
By what?
何によって？
historical memory
歴史的記憶
plus historical memory
プラス歴史的記憶
So some Tibetans next to me know
私の隣にいるチベット人は知っています
if you watch some survivors
何人かの生存者を見てみると
Two or three households have invaded your territory
2、3 世帯があなたの領土に侵入しました
no one lives next to your mountain
あなたの山の隣には誰も住んでいません
One day it suddenly started to smoke
ある日突然煙が出始めた
A few bereaved families came over there
そこへ数人の遺族がやって来た
then you don't mess with him
それなら彼に干渉しないでください
Because although there are two or three families
だって家族が２、３人いるのに
He randomly finds hundreds of people to help fight
彼は戦いに協力してくれる何百人もの人々をランダムに見つけます
Easy
簡単
Why?
なぜ？
It is by this combined with diachronic memory
通時記憶
so here
それでここで
In the entire Sichuan border area
四川省国境地帯全域
pineapple seed dill
パイナップルシードディル
are all in
全員入っています
already in Sichuan dialect
すでに四川弁です
scold strong and unreasonable people
強くて理不尽な人を叱る
What does it mean?
どういう意味ですか？
This is what it meant
これが意味したことです
The people from this side of Liangshan
梁山のこちら側の人々
so i just said
だから私はちょうど言った
My friend from the field is in Ezi Village, Xiaoxin Country
私の現地の友人は小新県のエジ村にいます
They are also called pineapple seeds
パイナップルの種とも呼ばれます
Actually they are not pineapple seeds
実はパイナップルの種ではありません
they are
彼らです
Because of being barbaric, I was scolded for stripping naked
野蛮だから裸にすると叱られた
Then other people's impression of them is
そうすると、他人の彼らに対する印象は、
Very able to mobilize people who increase capital to help fight
資金を増やして戦いを支援する人々を動員する能力が非常に高い
They are feared by all ethnic groups in this place
彼らはこの場所のあらゆる民族から恐れられている
then what about them
それでは彼らはどうですか
Each capital increase has its own family allowance
増資ごとに独自の家族手当が支給される
That is the name of men from generation to generation
それは代々男性の名前です
joint father and son
共同の父と息子
For example, he said that you see and hold the cloth
たとえば、布を見て手に取ると彼は言いました。
Take the cloth, take the insert, take the ink
布を取り、インサートを取り、インクを取ります
He even developed a way of changing memory
彼は記憶を変える方法さえ開発しました
so many important wars
とても多くの重要な戦争
Both Qianxi and ancestors are recorded in this kind of history
乾熙も祖先もこの種の歴史に記録されている
This is me from a visit to a person
これはある人を訪問したときの私です
He wrote a book called "I Am Between Ghosts and Gods"
彼は「私は幽霊と神々の間にいる」という本を書きました
i visit his son
私は彼の息子を訪ねます
his son wrote it with him
彼の息子が一緒にそれを書きました
He tells the history of their immediate family
彼は彼らの近親者の歴史を語ります
There are stories of brothers in this history
この歴史には兄弟の物語がある
But it's different from the gun bamboo
でも鉄砲竹とは違います
He all started with hero ancestors
すべては英雄の祖先から始まった
It all started with some heroic ancestors
すべては英雄的な先祖から始まりました
This is the score of the repertoire
これがレパートリーの楽譜です
you see the same
あなたも同じように見えます
Both father and son
父も息子も
This is a big death
これは大死だ
So why do you want to remember the history of the family?
では、なぜ家族の歴史を思い出したいのですか？
Because of the families in black they often have wars
黒人の家族のせいでよく戦争が起こる
I'm talking about the human ecology here
ここでは人間の生態について話しています
It has something to do with the large population here
それはここの人口の多さと関係がある
Many of them are wars between yin relatives
その多くは陰の親戚間の戦争です
Extraordinary
特別平凡
Those who were defeated moved away
負けた人は去って行った
So you remember the history of these old and new feuds
だからあなたはこれらの古くて新しい確執の歴史を覚えていますか
Can help people in the family to leave the same enemy
家族の人々が同じ敵から離れるのを助けることができる
Then for the survivors who love to sign
それから、署名が大好きな生存者の皆さんへ
Living through the history of the home
家の歴史を生きていく
can be found far away
遠くでも見つけることができます
That is, members of the family who help fight and borrow money
つまり、喧嘩をしたりお金を借りたりする家族の一員です。
Listen to what they say about women in general
一般の女性について彼らが言うことを聞いてください
It is not necessary to be home
家にいる必要はない
usually male
通常男性
But I also see some women who memorize their backs very well
しかし、自分の背中をよく覚えている女性もいます
It was the young man just now
さっきの若者だった
Once I went to a village with him
ある時彼と一緒に村に行った
He ended up being crippled by a drunk old lady
彼は結局酔った老婦人によって足が不自由になってしまいました
been talking for more than half an hour
30分以上話し続けた
Then the old lady let him go
それから老婦人は彼を行かせました
I just watched him pay the old lady five dollars
私はちょうど彼がおばあさんに 5 ドルをあげるのを見たところです
I said what's going on
何が起こっているのかと言いました
He said, oops, that old lady carried her home away from me.
彼は、「おっと、あのおばあさんが私から家まで運んでいったよ」と言いました。
I recited the last time when she was my aunt
彼女が叔母だったとき、私は最後に朗読した
I pay five dollars
私は5ドルを支払います
asked me to give him five bucks for a drink
飲み物代として5ドルくれるように私に頼んだ
So it's useful to look at the history
なので履歴を見ると便利です
this
これ
so let's take a look
それでは見てみましょう
These histories of the three ethnic groups we just looked at
先ほど見てきた 3 つの民族グループの歴史
and finally
そして最後に
I noticed that for nearly a hundred years
百年近く経って気づいた
At least that is if we don't know the earlier history
少なくともそれ以前の歴史を知らない場合には
very clear
非常に明確な
The distribution area of the survivors has been expanding
生存者の分布域は拡大中
It has something to do with it and the machine
それはそれと機械に関係があります
So this guy who lets us read history
歴史を読ませてくれるこの男
to think about a problem
問題について考える
That is to say, are we humans the earliest
つまり、私たちは人類の中で最も古いのですか？
live in a society like the stick gun
スティックガンのような社会で生きる
And history begins
そして歴史が始まる
Create more complex and larger societies
より複雑でより大きな社会を創造する
start to expand
拡大し始める
So we look inside the history
そこで歴史を振り返ってみましょう
In fact, there are real and fictional stories
実は、実話と架空の話があります
the most important is
最も重要なことは
Let's look at it and see what kinds of their local history
どのような郷土の歴史があるのか​​見てみましょう
in this historical narrative
この歴史的な物語の中で
often follow a certain structure
多くの場合、特定の構造に従います
Like the structure of the brothers we talked about
僕らが話した兄弟の構造のように
What kind of structure is there like a big bird?
大きな鳥のような構造はどのようなものでしょうか？
we can ask
私たちは尋ねることができます
Is it because the stick guns and their culture were relatively backward in the past?
昔はスティックガンとその文化が比較的後進的だったからでしょうか？
So they remember and uncle's
それで彼らは叔父のことを覚えています
history is not true
歴史は真実ではない
and looking for some narrative structure
物語の構造を探しています
Then don't we?
では、そうではないでしょうか？
not actually
実際はそうではなくて
I later wrote a book
その後本を書きました
It's called "Heroic Ancestors and Brotherly Nation"
それは「英雄的な祖先と兄弟国家」と呼ばれています。
is to analyze all those in Chinese history
中国の歴史のすべてを分析することです
History from the Emperor
天皇からの歴史
actually i found
実は私は見つけました
history as we know it
私たちが知っている歴史
Also looking for a narrative mode
ナラティブモードも探しています
History relative to sibling ancestors
兄弟の祖先と関連した歴史
what we know
私たちが知っていること
is a heroic ancestral history
先祖代々の英雄的な歴史です
These are two different histories
これらは2つの異なる歴史です
new product
新製品
Emerging history I mean a social culture
歴史的に出現したものとは、社会文化を意味します
it makes us unknowingly
それは私たちを無意識のうちにそうさせます
just looking for a certain pattern
特定のパターンを探しているだけです
to remember and write history
歴史を思い出し、書くこと
So look at this example I gave
それで、私が挙げたこの例を見てください
This is very famous in Chinese history
これは中国の歴史では非常に有名です
many historians
多くの歴史家
I always thought it was the real word
ずっと本当の言葉だと思ってた
A Heroic Ancestor in the Northeast
東北一個英雄祖先
Ji Zi, Prince of Yin, Runs to North Korea
殷の季子王子が北朝鮮へ逃亡
Be a hero to civilize the Korean people
朝鮮人民を文明化する英雄になろう
prince of a southeastern state
南東部の州の王子
run from here to here
ここからここまで走る
enlightened
啓発された
The heroic ancestors of the present Nanjing and Shanghai generations
現在の南京と上海の世代の英雄的な先祖たち
A general of the state of Chu ran from here to here
楚の将軍がここからここまで走った
becomes a conquest
征服になる
Kingdom
王国
become king here
ここで王になる
To the northwest, Tao Nutao of Qin State came here
北西、秦国のタオ・ヌタオがここに来た
The locals regard Tao as the king
地元の人々はタオを王とみなしている
think about it
考えてみてください
this history
この歴史
Is there any structure
何か構造はあるのでしょうか
is there a pattern
パターンはありますか
The first one has the pattern
1枚目にはパターンがあります
all a hero
みんな英雄
and all failed
そしてすべて失敗した
frustrated hero
挫折した主人公
right
右
Then if we know later
それで、後でわかったら
actually you see
実際に見てください
It is actually the symbol of these heroes
それは実際にこれらの英雄の象徴です
It corresponds to the Central Plains Huaxia at that time
当時の中原華夏に相当する。
these are the histories
これらは歴史です
both appear in probably
おそらく両方とも登場します
Between the 1st and 5th centuries AD
西暦1世紀から5世紀の間
In Shiji Hanshu and later Hanshu these
『史記漢書』と『後漢書』にはこうある。
in these records
これらの記録の中で
So it actually represents
したがって、それは実際に表します
Zhongyuan Huaxia's thoughts on the Quartet crowd
Zhongyuan Huaxia のカルテット観衆についての考え
Simply speaking
簡単に言えば
Zhongyuan Huaxia hopes that people on both sides
中原華夏氏は双方の人々に期待している
is part of Huaxia
華夏の一部です
So give them two more distinguished ancestors
それで、彼らにさらに二人の著名な先祖を与えてください
see if you want to accept
受け入れたいかどうかを確認してください
southwest a little hesitant
南西、少しためらいます
Give him a general of Chu
楚の将軍を与えよ
to this northwest
この北西へ
That's Tao Nu
それがタオヌーです
that's even worse
それはさらに悪いことです
so you see
ご覧のように
then this
それからこれ
Do you mean history?
歴史って言うんですか？
Do you care about this history?
この歴史が気になりますか？
Koreans now care about the history of the machine very much
今、韓国人はこの機械の歴史について非常に懸念している
so it's still fighting
だからまだ戦っている
since the twelfth century
12世紀以来
People on the Korean peninsula are very concerned about the history of the machine
朝鮮半島の人々は機械の歴史について非常に懸念しています
since modern times
近代以降
They have two discourses
彼らには2つの談話がある
First
初め
machine is myth
機械は神話だ
wrong
間違い
That's fine, just ignore him
大丈夫、彼を無視してください
The second argument is that
2 番目の引数は、
The machine is actually our Korean
この機械は実は私たちの韓国人です
In fact, the original territory
実は本来の領土は
In the current Chinese train
現在の中国の電車内
So Jilin Province belongs to our Korea
つまり、吉林省は私たちの韓国に属します
This must be controversial, right?
これは物議を醸すはずですよね？
how to explain history
歴史をどう説明するか
There is no dispute about Southeast
南東に関しては異論はない
Everyone believes that people in Jiangnan really believe in the history of Taibo Benwu
江南の人たちは太伯本武の歴史を本当に信じていると誰もが信じている
So you can still see the Taibo Temple when you go there
だから、そこに行くと今でも大宝寺を見ることができます
There are Taibo Temples in many places
各地に大宝寺がある
Southwest from Four Seasons
四季から南西
The four seasons of Zhuangqiao are written in all the square characters of Yunnan
荘橋の四季はすべて雲南の楷書で書かれている
Northwest they don't care
北西部の人たちは気にしない
I don't care what you say I am
あなたが何と言おうと私は気にしません
He doesn't care about this history of ignorance and foresight
彼はこの無知と先見性の歴史を気にしていません
So everyone pay attention to what I want to say
だからみんな、私の言いたいことに注目してね
The content of history may have truth
歴史の内容には真実があるかもしれない
But the main fiction lies in the relationship between history and the human rights in power
しかし、主要なフィクションは歴史と権力者の人権との関係にある
In other words, why do Koreans care about the machine?
言い換えれば、なぜ韓国人は機械にこだわるのでしょうか？
He thinks it seems that the machine has something to do with the current people in Korea
彼はこの機械が現在の韓国の人々と関係があるようだと考えている
In fact, no matter whether this history is true or not
実際、この歴史が真実かどうかは関係なく、
The biggest fiction lies in these characters in history
最大のフィクションは歴史上のこれらの登場人物にあります
Whether it's a brother or a hero
兄弟でもヒーローでも
relationship with present
現在との関係
that is a very big fiction
それはとても大きなフィクションです
Let's see
どれどれ
Creation and belief in the history of our brethren's ancestors
私たちの同胞の先祖の歴史に対する創造と信仰
The existence of this kind of gun bamboo
このような銃竹の存在
Everyone I didn't talk about here
ここで話せなかった皆さん
you can notice
あなたは気づくことができます
What is so special about this history?
この歴史の何がそんなに特別なのでしょうか？
this history because it is a past
この歴史は過去だから
then combine with now
それから今と組み合わせる
So in this history
だからこの歴史の中で
The reality created by that history is
その歴史が生み出した現実は
There is no distinction between conquerors and conquered
征服者と被征服者の区別はない
There is no distinction between old residents and new residents
古い住民と新しい住民の区別はありません
But the history of such heroic ancestors as we believe
しかし、私たちが信じているような英雄的な先祖の歴史は、
I can say
言えます
The so-called we are the whole world
いわゆる私たちは世界全体です
people of the so-called civilized world
いわゆる文明世界の人々
This is the hero we believe in
これが私たちが信じるヒーローです
Whether it's the emperor, Tan Jun, Chen Jinsihan, Abraham
皇帝であろうと、タン・ジュンであろうと、チェン・ジンシハンであろうと、アブラハムであろうと
What about the history of the holding group?
ホールディンググループの歴史についてはどうですか？
or Immigrant Heroes to the present May issue
または現在の5月号の移民ヒーロー
and the American history of the heroes who founded the country and unblocked the black slaves
そして建国し黒人奴隷を解放した英雄たちのアメリカの歴史
and emphasizing the history of Taiwan's history of the heroic attacks on the Policy Workers Awards
そして政策従事者賞に対する台湾の英雄的な攻撃の歴史を強調する。
They are all the products of a kind of heroic history.
それらはすべて、ある種の英雄的な歴史の産物です。
arises out of the above internal group distinction
上記の内部グループの区別から生じます
there are conquerors
征服者がいる
you just have to believe the history
歴史を信じればいいだけです
Now there is a distinction between the conqueror and the conquered
今、征服者と被征服者の間には区別がある
There is a distinction between old residents and new immigrants
古い居住者と新しい移民の間には区別がある
So actually do you think
それで実際にどう思いますか
What is the difference between those of us and those of the powerful or the Tibetans?
私たちと権力者やチベット人の違いは何でしょうか？
same structure
同じ構造
And what?
そして何？
Where is the same biggest fiction?
同じ最大のフィクションがどこにあるのでしょうか？
It's the relationship between the hero and the crowd
それは主人公と群衆の関係です
like in the US
アメリカのように
often the mayflower immigrant
多くの場合メイフラワー移民
It seems to be related to all the days
全ての日々に関係しているようだ
How could it be
どうしてそうなるのでしょう
right
右
In Taiwan, it seems that all the people from other provinces will tell you
台湾では他省の人はみんな教えてくれるようです。
Anti-China is related
反中も関係あるよ
All Hokkien people will be related to Zheng Chenggong
すべての福建人は鄭成功と親戚になるでしょう
Actually not
実際にはそうではありません
right
右
Those are all some imaginations generated through this kind of history
これらはすべて、このような歴史の中で生み出された想像です
So even if the heroic epic is true
たとえその英雄叙事が真実だったとしても
whatever those machines
それらの機械が何であれ
even if it's true
たとえそれが本当だとしても
He and the current group
彼と現在のグループ
For example, the relationship between the emperor and the Han people
例えば、皇帝と漢民族の関係。
are imagined and constructed
想像され構築される
so
それで
Finally I'm going to use this to illustrate my entire point above
最後に、これを使って上記の要点全体を説明します
It's like the movie Matrix
映画『マトリックス』みたい
the metrics
メトリクス
inside the plot
プロットの中
that plot is
そのプロットは
At that time, most people lived in the virtual world created by the computer city
当時、ほとんどの人はコンピューター都市が作り出した仮想世界の中で暮らしていました。
In fact, we are living in the real world constructed by history.
実際、私たちは歴史によって構築された現実の世界に生きています。
And we get a certain identity in this world
そして私たちはこの世界で確かなアイデンティティを得る
we're sending a memory
私たちは思い出を送っています
So because we believe in history
だから私たちは歴史を信じているから
Accepting one's social status on the fringes
自分の限界的な社会的地位の受け入れ
Like a person stepping on a sharp stone with bare feet
鋭い石を素足で踏むような
don't know pain
痛みを知らない
There is no movement of pulling the foot back
足を後ろに引く動作はありません
Or because we believe in and care about history
あるいは歴史を信じ、歴史を大切にしているから
we have something as
私たちは次のようなものを持っています
result of what we did
私たちがやったことの結果
create an appearance
外観を作成する
And let the world created by history
そして歴史が作った世界を
become more real
より現実的になる
so then
それで
How can we know the reality of the real world
現実世界の現実をどうやって知ることができるのか
How do you realize the meaning of your actions?
自分の行動の意味をどうやって理解しますか？
I've been advocating a kind of reflective historiography research lately
私は最近、ある種の内省的な歴史学の研究を提唱しています。
But mostly these are used in
しかし、これらはほとんどの場合に使用されます
research on ethnic minorities in China
中国の少数民族に関する研究
Actually my example just now
実際に今の私の例
the one i lifted
私が持ち上げたもの
also some ethnic minorities
一部の少数民族も
Let's say you accept a history
あなたが履歴を受け入れたとします
This history makes you a minority
この歴史があなたを少数派にする
Do you think I'm a minority?
私が少数派だと思いますか？
right?
右？
All your deeds have proved
あなたの行為はすべて証明されました
Your marginalization of this minority in the mainstream society
主流社会におけるこの少数派の疎外
more and more solid, more and more real
ますますしっかりとして、ますます現実的になる
you'll always be on the edge
あなたはいつも崖っぷちにいる
So the reflective historiography I advocate
つまり、私が提唱する内省的歴史学とは、
It is hoped that through some concepts and research methods
いくつかの概念と研究方法を通じて、
Let's not just be historians
ただの歴史家になるのはやめよう
I also hope that individuals in general will be able to reflect on our pre-existing historical knowledge
また、一般の人々が私たちの既存の歴史的知識を振り返ることができることを願っています。
to unearth some of the cognitive biases lurking in our minds
私たちの心に潜む認知バイアスを明らかにする
To understand the various social and cultural structures that influence our perception and construction of history
私たちの歴史の認識と構築に影響を与えるさまざまな社会的および文化的構造を理解する
In this way, our understanding of the reality of society and its historical changes
このようにして、社会の現実とその歴史的変化を理解することができます。
may have further understanding
さらに理解が深まるかもしれない
Thus there may be some reflective action
したがって、何らかの反射的な動作が発生する可能性があります
I want to create reflective knowledge
反省的な知を生み出したい
reflective cognition
反射的認知
and individuals capable of reflective action
反省的な行動ができる個人
Even if these actions are very small
たとえその行為がとても小さなものであっても、
can also gradually change the society
社会を少しずつ変えることもできる
thank you guys i will stop here today
ありがとう、今日はここで終わります
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
Thank you teacher for your wonderful speech
先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
i want to ask
聞きたいです
Suppose we learn according to reflection
反省に従って学習すると仮定します
Try to think about yourself or your society
自分自身や社会について考えてみる
How do I know if we all or myself
私たち全員か私自身かをどうやって知ることができますか
will get closer to the truth
真実に近づくだろう
Or do I jump from one surface appearance to another
それとも、ある表面の外観から別の表面の外観にジャンプしますか
I use an example from my book
私の本の例を使用します
A research method I suggest
私が提案する調査方法
In fact, this research method is also related to my multi-point fields.
実はこの研究方法は私の多点分野にも関係しています。
That is, if we take that history as a representation
つまり、その歴史を表現すると
That means I'm at Icgo's place
つまり、私はイッゴの家にいるということです
I observe their social reality
私は彼らの社会的現実を観察しています
I believe I'm not seeing the real image
本当の姿が見えていないのだと思う
That said I have a lot of my biases
つまり、私には多くの偏見があるということです
then I record their history
それから私は彼らの歴史を記録します
that's a sign
それはサインです
what is this like
これは何ですか
I watch it with an Out of the Mirror
アウト・オブ・ザ・ミラーで観てるよ
if i put my watch on the table
時計をテーブルの上に置いたら
If I look at this watch with an Out of the Mirror
アウト・オブ・ザ・ミラーでこの時計を見たら
Then all I saw was some of this Out of the Mirror
それから私が見たのは、このアウト・オブ・ザ・ミラーの一部だけでした
distorted some shapes
いくつかの形が歪んでいる
Then how can I get a better understanding
ではどうすればより深く理解できるでしょうか
The way I suggest is to move this Out of the Mirror
私が提案する方法は、これを鏡の外に移動することです
you move the angle of observation
観察角度を動かすと
or move it to see another object
または移動して別のオブジェクトを表示します
Then watch the change of its appearance
そして、その外観の変化を観察してください
Actually this is my field
実はここが私の畑なんです
I look everywhere
私はどこでも見ます
The image of society in every place
あらゆる場所にある社会のイメージ
But I'm not sure if my observation is right or wrong
しかし、私の観察が正しいか間違っているかはわかりません
But I record these their histories
でも私は彼らの歴史を記録します
or some myths and legends
またはいくつかの神話や伝説
I take these as appearances
私はこれらを外見として捉えています
Then I went to compare the changes in this appearance
次にこの外観の変化を比較してみました
Then this time actually this
じゃあ今度は実はこれ
I can't stress enough that
どれだけ強調しても足りません
This approach does not allow us
このアプローチでは、次のことはできません。
Absolutely understand the underlying phenomenon
根底にある現象を完全に理解する
But it can teach us about our biases
しかし、それは私たちの偏見について教えてくれます
That is the nature of this concave-convex mirror
それがこの凹凸鏡の性質です
Is this a concave mirror or a convex mirror?
これは凹面鏡ですか、それとも凸面鏡ですか?
I think this explanation should be ok
この説明で大丈夫だと思います
Thanks
ありがとう
He said it was devil's beer
彼はそれは悪魔のビールだと言いました
don't drink
飲まないでください
then i'll be fine
それなら大丈夫です
I went to buy Taiwan beer for him to drink
彼に飲むために台湾ビールを買いに行きました
Then just talk and start talking
それからただ話して話し始めてください
They came from Harbin in the northeast
彼らは東北のハルビンから来た
about the third century
3世紀くらい
also said education
教育とも言いました
They still call the Japanese devils
彼らは今でも日本人を悪魔と呼んでいます
Here is an example
ここに例があります
The second example is my brother in Shanghai
2番目の例は上海にいる私の兄弟です
he has a daughter
彼には娘がいます
I am ten years old and studying in Shanghai
私は10歳で上海に留学しています
He needs a red scarf when he goes to school
彼は学校に行くときは赤いスカーフが必要です
he told him honestly
彼は正直に彼に言った
This red scarf was
この赤いスカーフは
When the Japanese killed us Chinese
日本人が私たち中国人を殺したとき
Write the bonus of feelings first
感想のおまけを先に書く
we want to remember forever
私たちは永遠に覚えておきたい
This life impresses me deeply
この人生は私に深く感銘を与えます
The relationship between China and Japan is so deep
中国と日本の関係はとても深いです
They used hatred from childhood
彼らは子供の頃から憎しみを利用していた
come to teach how to treat the Japanese
日本人の扱い方を教えに来ました
How will the two succeed after renting
レンタル後の二人はどうやって成功するのか
how come
どうして
He used hatred at such a young age
彼は幼い頃から憎しみを行使した
What should I do if I recognize this renter?
このレンタル者を認識した場合はどうすればよいですか?
No, I saw the National Taiwan University History Hell Professor
いいえ、国立台湾大学歴史地獄教授を見ました
he has an article saying
彼は次のような記事を書いていた
Just don't teach history
歴史だけは教えないでください
Because it's all ideology
それはすべてイデオロギーだから
After teaching for a long time, I was right
長い間教えてきた私は正しかった
It's because others don't understand
それはすべて他の誰でもない
we want to hate
私たちは憎みたい
this worries me very much
これはとても心配です
Should we study history in the next generation?
次の世代では歴史を学ぶべきでしょうか？
Why do we care
なぜ気にするのか
what did we learn about history
私たちは歴史について何を学びましたか
What we learned about CSI
CSI について学んだこと
It turned out that many of them were not
彼らの多くはそうではないことが判明した
not all like this
すべてがそうではない
I took a lot of big classes
大きなクラスをたくさん受講しました
so i feel distressed
だから私は苦痛を感じています
many hours of driving
何時間も運転する
come ask the teacher to listen
先生に聞いてもらいに来てください
Thanks
ありがとう
I think that's the great challenge we historians face
それが私たち歴史家が直面する大きな課題だと思います
This indeed means that between each country
これはまさに、各国間で
will emphasize some of these histories
これらの歴史の一部を強調します
But at the same time we will forget some history
しかし同時に、私たちはいくつかの歴史を忘れてしまいます
So sometimes I will suddenly ask some mainland Chinese scholars
そこで時々、私は中国本土の学者に突然質問することがあります。
Some questions are like provocation
挑発のような質問もある
I said that a Jiangsu native once killed 800,000 of your Hebei native
江蘇省出身者がかつてあなたの河北省出身者80万人を殺害したと私は言いました
what no one knows
誰も知らないこと
I said that person's name is Xiang Yu
あの人の名前は項羽だと言った
Xiang Yu once killed that, this, 800,000
項羽はかつてあれを、これを、80万人を殺した
that's all
それで全部です
Because people think we're one country now
人々は私たちが今一つの国だと思っているから
right it's not important
そう、それは重要ではない
In fact, our history has been a little forgotten
実際、私たちの歴史は少し忘れられています
Then I'm thinking about the real history education
そこで私は本当の歴史教育について考えています
I think my ideal is
私の理想はこうだと思います
Of course we are still in a certain country
もちろん私たちはまだある国にいます
We are in Taiwan, or you are in China, right?
私たちは台湾にいるのですか、それともあなたは中国にいるのですか？
or every country, so your history
あるいはどの国でも、あなたの歴史
Still can't go too far beyond the interests of this country
この国の利益を越えることはまだできない
or something
か何か
But I feel our little child
でも私は私たちの幼い子供を感じます
in senior year
最高学年で
For example, in the third year of high school
例えば高校3年生のとき
or in college
または大学で
we will have this
これをいただきます
Combining historical memory with some aspects of social science
歴史の記憶と社会科学のいくつかの側面を組み合わせる
Basic courses in this category
このカテゴリーの基礎コース
let him know
彼に知らせてください
The relationship between his identity and history
彼のアイデンティティと歴史の関係
In this way, I feel that such a person
こうやってみると、そういう人って感じです
his future
彼の将来
There will be some reflective choices
いくつかの反射的な選択肢があるでしょう
rather than exactly this
まさにこれではなく
history of nationalism
ナショナリズムの歴史
caused by the kind
種類によって引き起こされる
This conflict between nations and nations
国家と国家の間のこの紛争
Of course we will also do some
もちろん私たちもやりますよ
Like me and Professor Huang Zhijing here
ここにいる私と黄志静教授のように
we also have cooperation
私たちにも協力があります
Do something like this in Northeast Asia
北東アジアでもこんなことやれよ
For example, history
たとえば、歴史
Let's see if we can come up with a historical explanation
歴史的な説明ができるか試してみましょう
Let Korea Japan China Taiwan
韓国、日本、中国、台湾にしましょう
Acceptable by several of our countries
いくつかの国で受け入れ可能
some northeast asian history
北東アジアの歴史
Especially about the so-called Manchuria
特にいわゆる満州については
Or the history of this place in the Northeast
あるいは東北のこの場所の歴史
because of the history here
ここの歴史があるから
It is related to the plot between several countries
複数の国間の陰謀に関係している
historical plot
歴史的なプロット
ask the professor
教授に聞く
very old history
非常に古い歴史
But because of the different generations
でも世代が違うから
Views and hatred of history
歴史観と憎悪
or what seems to keep evolving different views
または、さまざまな見解が進化し続けているように見えるもの
Is it the same with the angle?
角度も同じでしょうか？
Yes, of course that means
はい、もちろんそれはつまり
History and our personal
歴史と私たち個人
Actually what I just said
実は今私が言ったこと
with our personal identification
私たちの個人識別情報とともに
with where we are
私たちがいる場所と一緒に
Reality matters
現実が重要
And often when we write history
そして、私たちが歴史を書くとき、しばしば
we are influenced by some structures
私たちはいくつかの構造の影響を受けています
For example, I just mentioned a structure called historical emerging
たとえば、先ほど歴史的新興と呼ばれる構造について言及しました。
In fact, there are many
実際にはたくさんあります
let me give you an example
例をあげましょう
Chinese Fangzi Tradition
中国の方子の伝統
right
右
When Taiwan was included in the territory of the Qing Empire
台湾が清帝国の領土に組み込まれたとき
Usually magistrates come here
通常、裁判官はここに来ます
in any frontier area
どこの辺境地域でも
The first and foremost thing is called
何よりもまず最初に呼び出されるのは、
Gather local intellectuals to write square characters
地元の知識人を集めて四角い文字を書く
when you write square characters
四角い文字を書くとき
Note that square characters are a genre
四角文字はジャンルの一つなので注意
Genre means that it has a certain structure
ジャンルとは、特定の構造を持っていることを意味します
certain way of writing
ある特定の書き方
The genre of square characters naturally allows you to write a
四角い文字のジャンルなので自然に書くことができます。
Suitable square characters
適合的方字
And then turned Taiwan into a part of the whole big empire
そして台湾を巨大帝国の一部に変えた
This doesn't just happen in Taiwan
これは台湾だけで起こっているわけではありません
Any Yunnan is the same
雲南はどこも同じ
the way I've been looking for
私が探していた方法
It is a very interesting example that I studied before
これは私が以前に研究した非常に興味深い例です
the structure of history
歴史の構造
There is a guy from Yunnan who is very interesting
雲南出身のとても面白い男がいます
He has been very this and this all his life
彼は生涯を通じてこれこれこれだった
When it's time to indulge
贅沢をするとき
When it's time to be an official
公務員になるときは
Then teach when it's time to retire
そして引退するときが来たら教えてください
As a result, in later years
その結果、後年には
He is in charge of compiling a way of Yunnan
彼は雲南の道の編纂を担当している
As a result, he wrote a method
その結果、彼はメソッドを書きました
It's not suitable for square characters
四角い文字には不向きです
The result, the result, everyone knows what the result will be
結果、結果、結果がどうなるかは誰もが知っています
Everyone knows this word
誰もが知っているこの言葉
There is another organizational structure called Fang Zi Bureau
方子局と呼ばれる別の組織構造があります。
it's not his business
それは彼の仕事ではありません
it's a group of people thing
それは人々のグループのことです
As a result, his way was caught by his colleagues
その結果、彼のやり方は同僚にバレてしまった
this is not acceptable
これは受け入れられません
He left angrily
彼は怒って立ち去った
so everyone knows
だからみんな知ってるよ
Not just square characters
四角い文字だけじゃない
will guarantee you a history like square characters
四角い文字のような履歴を保証します
right
右
so everyone can
だから誰もができる
To find a certain rule and write it out
ある法則を見つけてそれを書き出すこと
This kind of organizational genre can also guarantee a square character
この種の組織ジャンルは四角い性格を保証することもできます
right
右
Then the text of this square character comes out
するとこの四角い文字の文字が出てきます
proves that place is part of the whole
場所が全体の一部であることを証明する
that's what tells us
それが私たちに伝えていることです
we write a lot
私たちはたくさん書きます
are influenced by some of our writing structures
私たちの文章構造の一部に影響を受けています
Our culture
私たちの文化
The impact of our various social organizations
さまざまな社会組織の影響
In fact, there is another one that I haven't explained very clearly here.
実は、ここであまり明確に説明していないもう 1 つがあります。
is the symbol
シンボルです
Symbolic meaning
象徴的な意味
In fact, it was mentioned just now
実は先ほども言いましたが、
like those brethren symbols
それらの兄弟のシンボルのように
pair hero symbol
ペアヒーローシンボル
symbol of a hero
英雄の象徴
Like those machines, taber
あの機械のように、テイバー
And the Jiang Zongzheng we talked about in Taiwan
そして台湾で話した江宗正について
Zheng Chenggong
鄭成功
inside each symbol
各シンボルの内側に
They all have some inner connotations in the eyes
それらはすべて目に内的な意味合いを持っています
not who it appears to be
誰であるかではない
and more meaning
そしてさらなる意味
affect our identification
私たちの識別に影響を与える
right
右
i will give him to you
彼をあなたにあげます
I ask you how much
いくらですかと尋ねます
I think our Chinese history
私たちの中国の歴史だと思います
because some things are
いくつかのことがあるからです
every emperor dies
どの皇帝も死ぬ
Only one head can change his name
名前を変更できるのは 1 つの頭だけです
you are sure
本当に
If the emperor had not died
天皇が死んでいなかったら
he doesn't know his life
彼は自分の人生を知らない
his future behavior is influenced by
彼の将来の行動は～に影響される
Because you think don't get a quick review
すぐにレビューを受けないと思うから
History should be leveled
歴史は平準化されるべきだ
This concept seems to be unique to China.
この考え方は中国独特のもののようです。
don't understand this
これはわかりません
In addition to that
それに加えて
same basis
同じ根拠
form of confirmation
確認フォーム
like until the qing dynasty
清の時代までみたいに
The history of the Ming Dynasty was written by the Qing Dynasty
明王朝の歴史は清王朝によって書かれた
The Republic of China should write history
中華民国は歴史を書くべきだ
For example, the history of the Republic of China
例えば中華民国の歴史
Who is he to write
誰を書くのか
these are some questions
これらはいくつかの質問です
In fact, I feel like Guoshu people, the original staff should do this
実際、郭州人はオリジナルのスタッフがこれを行うべきだと感じています
He's not doing it now, probably can't do it, can't do it
彼は今はやっていない、おそらくできない、できない
This is what seems to have been done historically
これは歴史的に行われていたことのようです
is it possible to invite them to come
彼らを招待することはできますか
I may only be able to answer part of your question, the question about verification
ご質問の一部、確認に関するご質問しかお答えできない場合がございます。
Confirmation is also a genre like the one I just mentioned
確認も先ほど言ったようなジャンルです
It also has a certain format
一定の形式もあります
And this is very interesting, in my research on reflective history
これは非常に興味深いことです、歴史を振り返ることについての私の研究では
That is to say, my interpretation of some historical texts
つまり、いくつかの歴史文書に対する私の解釈です。
It may be different from the general and traditional interpretation methods
一般的かつ伝統的な解釈方法とは異なる場合があります
I'll treat it as one, it'll correspond to a situation
一つとして扱います 状況に応じて対応します
That is, there is a corresponding relationship between text and context
つまり、テキストとコンテキストの間には対応関係があります。
Just under a certain context, you will generate such text
特定のコンテキストの下で、そのようなテキストを生成します
that historical text
その歴史的文書
If that kind of structural context is like the Central Plains Empire
そういう構造的文脈が中原帝国のようなものだとしたら
it produces a structured text
構造化されたテキストが生成されます
That's the proof we're talking about you just mentioned
それが私たちが話していることです、あなたが今言った確認です。
So you see that the emergence of the confirmation is in the Qin Han Empire
つまり、確認の出現は秦漢帝国であることがわかります
Right, when China's first unified empire emerged
そう、中国初の統一帝国が誕生したときのことだ。
it appeared
それが登場しました
Then when it comes to Qing History, it can barely become the last proof
そして清の歴史に関して言えば、それはかろうじて最後の証拠となり得る
You can see that text and context are consistent
テキストとコンテキストが一貫していることがわかります
right
右
When the context of the entire Central Plains Empire appeared, it was confirmed to appear
中原帝国全体の文脈が出現した時点で出現が確認された
The Central Plains Empire is over
中原帝国は終わった
it just ends
ただ終わるだけだ
So it has a corresponding relationship
つまり対応関係がある
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
If we're going to write Taiwan's history or something now
今台湾の歴史とか書くなら
Of course, it is impossible for us to find the format of proof to write
もちろん、書くべき証明の形式を見つけることは不可能です。
even in mainland China
中国本土でも
I'm thinking there's one that everyone can be very suspicious of paying attention to.
誰もが注意を払うことに非常に疑問を抱く可能性があるものがあると思います。
This is a large-scale compilation in mainland China
中国本土での大規模編集です
Bi-Historical Project
親史工程
So what kind of family history will be compiled in the end?
果たして、最終的にはどのような家族史が編纂されるのでしょうか？
This pro-history and the original official history structure
この親史と本来の正史の構造
what difference does it make
どんな違いがあるの
I think that tells us a lot
それは私たちに多くのことを教えてくれると思います
Excuse me
すみません
give that first
先給那個
I am like this
私はこんな感じです
I read a little history myself because I'm an amateur
素人なので歴史を少し読んでみました
that is sometimes a little worrying
それは時々少し心配です
Are we advocating a historical attitude
私たちは歴史的な態度を主張していますか
when we study history
私たちが歴史を勉強するとき
be humble
謙虚になりなさい
That is to say, our Chinese nation is not that great
つまり、私たちの中華民族はそれほど偉大ではありません
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
Even the nations are really not so great
国家さえ実はそれほど偉大ではない
when we read history
私たちが歴史を読むとき
When washing history, the so-called formal
歴史を洗うとき、いわゆるフォーマル
It will shape our national self-confidence
それは私たちの国家の自信を形成するでしょう
let them
彼らにさせてください
For example, from the perspective of various ethnic plots involving various aspects
たとえば、さまざまな側面を含むさまざまな民族陰謀の観点から
But because this situation is different from other countries
でも他の国とは事情が違うので
There will be quotas and conflicts
割り当てや競合が発生する可能性があります
So shall we adopt a more modest historical attitude?
それでは、私たちはもっと謙虚な歴史的態度をとるべきでしょうか？
can be compared
比較できる
like in this sense
この意味でのように
It is very meaningful for you to study the history of ethnic minorities
少数民族の歴史を学ぶことはあなたにとって非常に有意義です
because it can be compared to some
何かと比較できるから
Chauvinism of the Han Nationality Chauvinism of the Great Qing Dynasty
漢民族の排外主義 大清朝の排外主義
Looking at the history of this minority
この少数派の歴史を振り返ると、
Like you take this Otto
あなたがこのオットーを受け取るように
can have a clearer career
より明確なキャリアを築くことができる
Is this attitude true?
この態度は本当ですか？
OK
OK
Thanks
ありがとう
My ideas may be more radical than yours
私のアイデアはあなたのアイデアよりも過激かもしれません
I just think we have to reflect on those
ただそれらについては反省する必要があると思います
Whether it is the Chinese nation or all nations
それが中華民族であろうと、すべての民族であろうと、
or the concept of ethnic minorities
あるいは少数民族の概念
I was in a speech not long ago
少し前にスピーチをしていました
tell my audience
聴衆に伝えてください
We even develop a sense of beauty
美的感覚も養われます
on a hillside
丘の中腹にある
How many of these thatched cottages are there?
この茅葺き小屋は何軒あるでしょうか？
or a stone house
または石造りの家
we think it is a kind of beauty
私たちはそれが一種の美しさだと考えています
Because this is called the little tree nation
ここは小さな木の国と呼ばれているから
Or the settlement of the Round Treemen
あるいはラウンド・ツリーマンの居住地
And if there is a sun room
そしてサンルームがあれば
We feel that the unbeautiful destroys the beauty
私たちは、美しくないものが美しさを破壊すると感じます
why do we have to
なぜそうしなければならないのか
They all live in this very high-end sun room
彼らは皆、この非常に高級なサンルームに住んでいます
we encourage some people
私たちは何人かの人々を励ます
to practice that beauty
その美しさを実践するために
to live in thatched huts and stone huts
茅葺き小屋や石造りの小屋に住む
Why do we call culture
なぜ文化と呼ぶのか
Our culture is placed in the Palace Museum
私たちの文化は故宮博物院に展示されています
or where is this
またはここはどこですか
inside these museums
これらの美術館の中で
And some people are called the little tree people
そして、リトル・ツリー・ピープルと呼ばれる人々もいます
round tree people
丸い木の人々
must be in daily life
日常生活の中にあるはず
to practice their culture
彼らの文化を実践する
practice their traditional culture
彼らの伝統文化を実践する
Actually I think we have a lot of this
実際、私たちはこれをたくさん持っていると思います
such a misunderstanding
そんな誤解
or this illusion
あるいはこの幻想
all because of our commitment to the entire
すべては私たちの全体への取り組みのおかげです
This society does not have a real understanding of some of our appearances
この社会は私たちの外見の一部について真の理解を持っていません
My name is Lin and my name is Lin Nonghai
私の名前は林、私の名前は林農海です
my teacher has a historical perspective
私の先生は歴史的観点を持っています
Now in this world, let's say IS
今この世界でISとしましょう
They kill people indiscriminately
彼らは無差別に人を殺します
without this humanity
この人間性がなければ
Then the United States should help them
それなら米国も彼らを助けるべきだ
He also attacked IS
ISも攻撃していたことが判明
But there are many refugees
しかし難民もたくさんいる
America is empathetic too
アメリカも同情的だ
$4 billion and more recently $4 billion
40億ドル、最近では40億ドル
to finish this
これを終わらせるために
But the Soviet Union
しかしソ連は
He's going to this series
彼はこのシリーズに参加する予定です
do you know
あなたは知っていますか
To help IS, or how to help, to unrest
ISを助けるか、または不安を助ける方法
so i want to remember this
だからこれを覚えておきたい
I think of Huaguo National Limitable
華国国家有限公司を思い出します
that miserable world
あの悲惨な世界
I've read a lot of the writings of this legacy country
私はこの伝統的な国の著作をたくさん読みました
this inside this
この中にこれ
Let's do some research and see what can be done
調査して何ができるかを見てみましょう
this to solve
これで解決する
I'm not trying to panic, and I'm not here to help over there.
私はパニックに陥るつもりはありませんし、向こうを助けるためにここにいるわけでもありません。
Help here, expand your own establishment
ここを手伝って、自分の施設を拡大してください
have empathy, have sympathy
共感を持つ、同情する
To see how the world will change
世界がどう変わるかを見るために
Thanks
ありがとう
thanks i think this we all agree
ありがとう、これは私たち全員が同意すると思います
you are judging by history
あなたは歴史から判断している
I look at history
歴史を見てみます
So for this IS question
したがって、このISの質問については、
this
これ
i didn't
私はしませんでした
I can't say his brother because I don't do research on that
弟については調べていないので言えません
but i can only say
でも言えることは
Do you feel a little hot
少し暑いと思いますか
good
良い
I will briefly talk about some of my views
私の見解のいくつかを簡単にお話します
In fact, not long ago I
実は少し前に私も
Because I was in Yinchuan not long ago
ついこの間まで銀川にいたから
I also gave a speech in a university for nationalities
国籍別の大学でもスピーチをしました
Many of my audience are muslims
私の聴衆の多くはイスラム教徒です
The topic I'm talking about is related to my gun post research.
私が話しているテーマは、私の砲塔研究に関連しています。
There's a Poison Cat Tale Over the Gun Post
銃のポストには毒猫の物語がある
Lets say some women in a village are poison cats
ある村の女性が毒猫だとしましょう
In fact, I simply say
実際、私はただ言います
This kind of legend is the same as the story of the witch in the West
この種の伝説は西洋の魔女の物語と同じです
the real behind it
その背後にある本物
This is if it is a text
テキストの場合はこれです
This legend is treated as a text
この凡例はテキストとして扱われます
Behind the context
背景にあるもの
It is the marginal status of women in a community.
それはコミュニティにおける女性の周縁的な地位です。
And such a community is a place that emphasizes purity
そしてそのようなコミュニティは純粋さを重視する場所です
A community that emphasizes boundaries
境界線を重視するコミュニティ
will produce this
これを生産します
We're a phenomenal phenomenon in research
私たちは研究において驚異的な現象です
in this way
この上
In fact, there are many problems of this kind in this IS
実はこのISにはこの種の問題が多々ある
In fact, it's all about the purity in it.
実際、大切なのはその純粋さです。
everyone is not just this
これだけでなく
In fact, in many human groups
実際、多くの人間の集団では、
Everyone emphasizes boundaries, emphasizing purity
誰もが境界を強調し、純粋さを強調します
In fact, this is a lot of human
実際、これは多くの人間です
These suspicions, some of the roots of violent conflict
こうした疑惑、暴力的紛争の根源の一部
this subtitle of my speech
私のスピーチのこのサブタイトル
It is called the source of fear, suspicion and violence of human beings.
それは人間の恐怖、猜疑心、暴力の根源とも言われています。
but today there is no way to talk about this
しかし今日はこれについて話す方法はありません
If you are interested, you can find me
興味があれば、私を見つけてください
In fact, you hit the poisonous cat on the Internet
実はネットで毒猫を叩いていたんですね
After that there was a lot of discussion
その後も色々な議論がありました
In my book "Shooting Between Han and Tibetans"
私の著書『漢人とチベット人の銃撃』の中で
There's also a specialization on that poison cat phenomenon.
あの毒猫現象に関する専門分野もあります。
Thanks
ありがとう
Yuan Shihao, I would like to ask how the difference in the history of the ancestors came about
袁世豪さん、祖先の歴史の違いがどのようにして生じたのか聞きたいです。
Then why now it seems that the history of most countries is built on the history of heroic ancestors
では、なぜ今、ほとんどの国の歴史は英雄的な先祖の歴史に基づいて構築されているように見えるのでしょうか？
Then it seems that most of the aborigines and primitive tribes we think of are based on the history of brothers
そうすると、私たちが考える先住民や原始部族のほとんどは兄弟の歴史に基づいているようです。
It is brothers, ancestors, history is the main
兄弟、先祖、歴史がメインです
So is there any type of ancestry history other than these two? Thanks
それでは、これら 2 つ以外に先祖の歴史の種類はありますか? ありがとう
This question is very good, just now I didn't make it very clear, I can add now
この質問はとても良いです。今、あまり明確にできませんでした。今追加できます。
So think about it, these two are different societies, one is a continuous society
考えてみてください、この 2 つは異なる社会で、1 つは連続した社会です
That is, you have a ruling class and then there are layers of rulers underneath
つまり、支配階級があり、その下に支配者の層が存在するということです。
Then there are conquerors, there are conquered, there are first comers, there are last comers
そして征服者もいる、征服される者もいる、先着者もいる、後発者もいる
If you belong to such a society, the history you believe in is that kind of heroic history
そういう社会に属しているなら、あなたが信じる歴史はそういう英雄的な歴史だ
So you can see that all our complex societies, our so-called civilized societies have a history like this
つまり、私たちの複雑な社会、いわゆる文明社会にはすべてこのような歴史があることがわかります。
Right? That history creates first comers and latecomers
そうでしょう? その歴史が先着者と後発者を生み出します
Whether it's American history or Taiwanese history, it's the same
アメリカの歴史でも台湾の歴史でもそれは同じ
The history of the South is the same
南部の歴史も同じだ
But this is the history of the gunman, the brother and ancestor on the other side of the gun
しかし、これはガンマン、銃の向こう側にいる兄弟、そして先祖の歴史です
give us a great inspiration
私たちに素晴らしいインスピレーションを与えてください
That is to say, human society can be like this
つまり人間社会はこうなり得るのです
If you believe simple history like that
そんな単純な歴史を信じるなら
In real people, it is
現実の人々では、それは
No first comer, no latecomer, no ruler, no ruled
先着者なし、後発者なし、支配者なし、被支配者なし
right?
右？
Because that history is that simple
その歴史は単純だから
So if this is about the development of a human society
これが人間社会の発展に関するものであるならば
Actually, a subject that I am very interested in now
実は今とても興味があるテーマなのですが、
I also hope that sometimes if young scholars in the social sciences or history
また、社会科学や歴史の若い学者が時々、
Maybe this problem is not something I can solve
もしかしたらこの問題は私に解決できるものではないかもしれません
Maybe it can be solved in your time
あなたの時間内に解決できるかもしれません
because it's a big problem
それは大きな問題だから
Is human society the earliest
人間社会が一番古いのか
It is in a society that is planned one by one like the history of brothers and ancestors
兄弟や先祖の歴史のように一つ一つ計画されていく社会です
fight each other in the area
地域内で互いに戦う
right
右
dare not go out
あえて外に出ないでください
Since when did humans develop into a complex society
人類はいつから複雑な社会に発展したのか
when did it start
いつ始まりましたか
Humans are brave enough to go out
人間は外に出る勇気がある
by blood memory
血の記憶によって
You can find people of the same race to help you in far away places
遠く離れた場所でも助けてくれる同じ人種の人々を見つけることができます
that i think
私が思うこと
Do you feel that in-depth research
綿密な調査を感じますか
This kind of Yizu
こんなyizu
This comparison between them and guns
彼らと銃の比較
maybe a clue
たぶん手がかり
When explaining the Lord first
最初に主について説明するとき
stuck in 1950
1950年に行き詰まった
in the 1960s
1960年代に
It seems that after the founding of the Communist Party of China
中国共産党創設後のようです
as if there was a break
まるで休憩があったかのように
Then I thought of my two or three brothers who had studied with Mr. Liu Shaohua before.
そこで私は、以前に劉少華氏に師事した2、3人の兄弟のことを思い出しました。
He also talks about the two-three-one family
彼はまた、2つまたは3つのことについて話します
He said that after the 1950s and 1960s, the two or three ones
彼は、1950 年代と 1960 年代以降、2 つまたは 3 つのものが増えたと言いました。
It seems to be the very traditional habit that is traditional in the mountains now
それは今では山の中で伝統的に行われている非常に伝統的な習慣のようです
These changes by modernity or total regime
近代化または全体的な体制によるこれらの変化
will affect his old tradition and model
彼の古い伝統とモデルに影響を与えるだろう
The teacher's story just now actually stopped at a specific number of years
さっきの先生の話、実は何年かで止まっているんです。
I want to know what happened after that
その後どうなったのか知りたい
Or what the teacher just said
あるいは先生が今言ったこと
Does the process of the speech just now still exist?
今のスピーチの過程はまだ残っていますか？
If it does not exist, it is now newly created some memories of his family to change
存在しないなら、今新たに作られた家族の思い出を変える
Or is it a very formal regime to influence
それとも、影響を与えるための非常に正式な体制なのでしょうか？
Then this is the so-called teacher
それからこれがいわゆる先生です
situational structure
状況構造
and then go on to something that has a realistic structure
次に、現実的な構造を持つものに進みます。
ok , ok , that ' s a good question
わかりました、わかりました、それは良い質問です
Let me say it again, that is to say, there are indeed some changes in the structure of reality now
もう一度言いますが、つまり、今、現実の構造には確かに変化が起きています。
So, I say that culture is actually an appearance
つまり、文化とは実際には外見であると私は言います
There is a change in that appearance
その姿に変化が
In fact, a simple example
実際に、簡単な例を挙げると、
That is to say, the worship of the three gods of the gun bamboo we just talked about
つまり、先ほどの鉄砲竹三神の信仰です。
right?
右？
What about now, because their country
今はどうですか、なぜなら彼らの国は
Especially after the 2008 earthquake
特に2008年の地震の後
Bring down all the spears and bamboos on many mountains
多くの山の槍と竹をすべて倒す
So its traditional fields are useless
したがって、従来の分野は役に立たない
But, there's another big support competition
しかし、また大きなサポートコンテストがあります
It is from the grass, from me, everyone knows that the east from the grass
それは草からです、私からです、草から東であることは誰もが知っています
From the time when I first went to Gunzhu to do field work
初めて郡主にフィールドワークに行った頃から
Two yuan a piece, now forty-five to fifty yuan a piece
1個2元、今は1個45～50元
From the price of grass so high
牧草の値段が高す​​ぎるので
Who cares about those boundaries on the hill?
丘の上の境界線なんて誰が気にするでしょうか？
right? and then everybody's pushing that line
そうでしょう？そしてみんながその線を押し進めています
Then everyone will stop worshiping the Three Gods
そうすれば誰もが三神を崇拝するのをやめるだろう
it is very simple
それはとても簡単です
That is to say, the support boundary between the human beings represented by the three gods
つまり、三神に代表される人類間の支援境界である。
This has all been changed
これはすべて変更されました
Then this worship of the three gods is no longer remembered.
そして、この三神への崇拝はもはや記憶されなくなります。
But there are some social realities that still exist
しかし、依然として存在する社会的現実もいくつかあります
For example, I thought it was funny when I was doing fields over there
例えば、あそこで畑をやっていて面白いと思ったんです。
It's from Liang Shanzhou and Ababa Zhou.
梁山州とアババ周からです。
Some of the behaviors of some local cadres I have seen are different
私が見た一部の地元幹部の行動の一部は異なっていた
The local cadres on the Abazhou side are often people who take care of their hometown
峨州側の地元幹部は故郷を大切にする人が多い
The local cadres on Liang Shanzhou's side are all from the same family.
梁山州側の地元幹部は皆同じ一族の出身だ。
One is a society that pays attention to space
一つは宇宙に注目する社会
A society that values kinship
血縁を大切にする社会
You see it's still like this
ほら、まだこんな感じだよ
some things still haven't changed
いくつかのことは変わっていない
But basically because the state's involvement is too deep now
しかし基本的には、現在は国家の関与が深すぎるためです。
This change is very big
この変化はとても大きいです
but we have this
しかし、私たちはこれを持っています
Let me give you another small example
もう一つ小さな例を挙げましょう
you know we're going to reflect
私たちが反省することはわかっているでしょう
not necessarily in this
必ずしもこの中にあるわけではありません
Before the intervention of contemporary national and ethnic classifications
現代の国民的および民族的分類が介入する前
It's like a utopia, it's not
ユートピアのようでいて、そうではない
That is to say, that kind of small village does not necessarily look like an ideal country in society.
つまり、そのような小さな村は社会的には必ずしも理想的な国には見えないのです。
I once chatted with an old man who was fighting with guns
銃を持った老人とおしゃべりしたことがある
He told me about the past where they lived in fear of violence
彼は暴力に怯えながら暮らしていた過去について語った
In this endless war between the village and the village
村と村の終わりのない戦争で
Then he talked and finally he suddenly smiled wryly
それから彼は話し、最後に突然苦笑した
like self-deprecating
自虐的なような
He said it was because we people in the past had no knowledge
それは私たち昔の人が何も知らなかったからだと彼は言いました
Didn't know we were one nation
私たちが国家だということを知りませんでした
So what I heard at that time was
それで、その時聞いたのは、
shouting hairs stand on end
叫び声が逆立って
why?
なぜ？
as if we were deconstructing this knowledge system
まるでこの知識体系を解体しているかのように
Right? A lot of our research is deconstructing this knowledge system
そうでしょう? 私たちの研究の多くは、この知識システムを解体するものです
deconstructing the national identity
国家アイデンティティの解体
Why do we do this?
なぜこれを行うのでしょうか?
right?
右？
In fact, why did I emphasize a kind of reflective identification later on?
実際、なぜ私は後になってある種の内省的同一化を強調したのでしょうか?
that is
あれは
You still agree that you are a gunman
あなたはまだ自分がガンマンであることに同意しています
You still agree that you are a Mongolian pawn
あなたはまだ自分がモンゴルの手駒であることに同意しています
but
しかし
I don't necessarily have to accept what you say
必ずしもあなたの言うことを受け入れる必要はない
The history of my mainline defeating your mainline
私のメインラインがあなたのメインラインを破った歴史
it means i have a new way of thinking about history
それは私が歴史について新しい考え方を持っていることを意味します
under this idea
この考えの下で
i admit i am a gunman
私は自分がガンマンであることを認めます
I admit that I am a Mongolian soldier
私は自分がモンゴルの兵士であることを認めます
right
右
that for what you just said
それはあなたが今言ったことのためです
i have a bit of that what
私はそれを少し持っています
Carmen
カルメン
you just mentioned
あなたは今言いました
There is a place where there are those brothers
あの兄弟がいる場所がある
Their history is different
彼らの歴史は違います
right
右
Then I'm thinking that his brother may not be the brother on the snowman
そうすると、彼の弟は雪だるまの弟ではないのではないかと思います。
or that is to say
あるいはつまり
Didn't you just say that?
さっきそう言ったじゃないですか？
That is to say, after he signed
つまり、彼が署名した後、
Then his kinship is all over again.
その後、彼の親族関係は再び始まります。
It is possible that it was signed by a different place.
別の場所で署名された可能性があります。
That's called brother
それを兄弟と呼びます
But it's not actually the student's brother
でも実は生徒の弟ではないんです
So they will have different histories
だから彼らには違う歴史があるだろう
Maybe it's because of this
もしかしたらこれのせいかもしれない
This is a
これは
Then again, you just mentioned
それから、先ほどもおっしゃいましたが、
have a nation
国家を持っている
He memorized the long, long history of this main line
彼はこの本線の長い長い歴史を覚えていた
right
右
You remind me of that America
あなたはあのアメリカを思い出させます
There used to be a book called Healing, right?
昔、『ヒーリング』という本がありましたよね。
He remembers the black man
彼は黒人のことを覚えている
has been swinging his long, long history
彼の長い長い歴史を揺るがしてきた
That is to say, this thing is very similar to
つまり、これは非常によく似ています
That may mean that some ethnic groups
それは、一部の民族グループが
he is very
彼はとても
this is good at
これは上手です
Just remember this long, long history
この長い長い歴史を思い出してください
This is my second point
これが私の2番目のポイントです
Then again, that is
それからまた、つまり、
you just mentioned this confirmation
あなたは今この確認について言及しました
I actually hid the one in Zhongan Jie
実は中安街に隠してたんです
The one in the ancient book in Zhonganjie
中安街の古書に載っているもの
so we see confirmation
確認が取れました
I found out that it is the proof of China
それが中国の証拠だと分かった
he is actually
彼は実際にいます
that first step
その最初の一歩
we are talking now
私たちは今話しています
It is a history written independently by the writer himself.
著者自身が独自に書いた歴史書です。
written from the writer's point of view
作家の視点から書かれた
History of Mathematics from Chinese
中国語からの数学の歴史
Basically he is from the perspective of the royal family
基本的に彼は王室の視点に立っている
rewrite history
歴史を書き換える
So in Chinese political history
中国の政治史では
In fact there is a prejudice
実は偏見がある
These emperors of China are all placed in this season
これらの中国の皇帝はすべてこの季節に配置されています
In Chinese history, there is a calendar behind him
中国の歴史には彼の後ろに暦がある
He put the surrounding countries in the calendar
彼は周辺諸国をカレンダーに入れました
Calendar is to put together with ordinary famous people
カレンダーは一般の有名人と一緒に作るものです
he does not have an equal status
彼は同等の地位を持っていない
to treat other surrounding countries
他の周辺国を治療する
I think like the CCP now
今は中国共産党と同じように考えています
He will not let the president of Taiwan
彼は台湾総統を許さない
Go to an international conference and show up together
国際会議に行って一緒に出席する
This mentality is the same as that written in history
このメンタリティは歴史に書かれたものと同じです
The policy mentality is the same
政策の考え方は同じです
right
右
He finally said that I am the country
彼はついに私が国だと言った
then you are not a country
それならあなたは国ではありません
we two leaders cannot sit together
私たち二人の指導者は一緒に座ることはできません
just the same
全く同じで
So I think our Taiwan
だから私たちの台湾は
can actually do one thing
実際に一つのことができる
That is to say, from the perspective of the common people and the people
つまり、庶民、庶民の視点から見ると、
to rewrite history
歴史を書き換える
including Chinese history
中国の歴史も含めて
Japanese history
日本歷史
korean history
韓国の歴史
And the history of Southeast Asian countries
そして東南アジア諸国の歴史
then come on again
それからまた来てください
Inside our wicked traffic room
邪悪な交通室内
we are now in fact
私たちは今実際にいます
There are very few exchanges with countries in Southeast Asia
東南アジア諸国との交流はほとんどない
should be in high school
高校生であるべきだ
The history of these Southeast Asian countries should be handed over
東南アジア諸国の歴史は引き継がれるべきだ
We now have a close relationship with this country
私たちは今この国と密接な関係を築いています
There are many foreign brides
外国人花嫁も多い
and foreign workers
そして外国人労働者
But we know very little about them
しかし、私たちは彼らについてほとんど知りません
So we should use the new angle
したがって、新しい角度を使用する必要があります
to rethink historical transactions
過去の取引を再考する
i think i simply answer
ただ答えるだけだと思う
Your two previous questions are all right
前の 2 つの質問は大丈夫です
first bro host stuff
初めてのブラザーホストのもの
that's just a historical memory
それはただの歴史的な記憶です
that doesn't mean that means
それは意味ない それは意味する
really some kind of blood relationship
本当にある種の血のつながりがある
That has nothing to do with real history
それは実際の歴史とは何の関係もありません
But that doesn't mean he's not real
しかし、それは彼が本物ではないという意味ではありません
Which means it doesn't matter if it's real or not.
つまり、本物かどうかは関係ないということです。
What matters is how you narrate history
重要なのは歴史をどう語るかだ
Actually they are telling us
実際、彼らは私たちにこう言っています
when his family history
彼の家族歴のとき
I have noticed my friend of Aiqigou
アイチーゴウの友人に気づきました
very interesting
とても興味深い
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
How is my waist bully with his second brother and eldest brother?
次兄と長兄に私の腰はどうですか？
Or what about my grandfather and his elder brother and second brother
あるいは私の祖父とその兄と次兄はどうでしょうか
the one he told us about
彼が私たちに話してくれたこと
It's about my grandfather's generation.
私の祖父の世代の話です。
Let's talk about our father's generation
私たちの父親の世代について話しましょう
that statement is different
その発言は違います
We all start with a grandfather
私たちは皆、おじいさんから始まります
My grandfather had two sons or something
私の祖父には二人の息子か何かがいました
they are not
ではない
He is just parallel to start like this
彼はこのように始めるのにちょうど平行です
Then I noticed those
それから私はそれらに気づきました
that is to say it is a memory
つまり思い出です
That means you can't think that
つまり、そんなことは考えられないということです
a patterned memory
パターン化された記憶
like this one of the earliest
これのように、最も初期のもの
In Tubo's document "Historical Collection of Han and Tibetan"
トゥボ氏の文書「漢人とチベット人の歴史コレクション」の中で
He went to record some of China's
彼は中国の音楽の一部を録音しに行った
The history of the Tang Dynasty
唐の歴史
He also said that a certain emperor in the Tang Dynasty
彼はまた、唐の時代のある皇帝はこう言いました。
It's the oldest of his brothers
彼の兄弟の中で一番年上です
We saw this and thought it was weird
私たちはこれを見て、奇妙だと思いました
Because Chinese literature does not record in this way
中国文学ではこのように記録されていないため、
right
右
He still uses this narrative
彼は今でもこの物語を使っています
what you just said
あなたが今言ったこと
That is to say, some are not of a certain nationality
つまり、特定の国籍を持たない人もいます
Especially good at recording relatively long histories
特に比較的長い履歴を記録するのが得意
I think this is human ecology
これが人間の生態だと思う
in a human ecology
ある人間の生態の中で
Some people need to memorize a longer history
もっと長い歴史を記憶する必要がある人もいる
OK
OK
Professor Wei, may I ask?
魏先生、聞いてもいいですか？
Thanks
ありがとう
I have three questions to ask
3つ質問したいことがあります
In the early 1980s, it happened that the two sides of the Taiwan Strait
1980 年代初頭、台湾海峡の両側が偶然にも
After the tee you have studied in the past
過去に勉強したティーの後
Yours has been there for ten years
あなたのものはそこに10年間あります
How to apply for the source of funding
資金源の申請方法
the second one is
2つ目は
How do they see us Taiwanese
彼らは私たち台湾人をどのように見ていますか
Do they treat us as Han Chinese or
彼らは私たちを漢民族として扱うのでしょうか、それとも
still fled
まだ逃げた
political group
政治団体
How did you see this scholar from Taiwan?
この台湾出身の学者をどう思いましたか？
Will there be this feeling of being neglected?
無視されているという感覚はあるでしょうか？
the third one is
3つ目は
because they you just mentioned they are
あなたが今言ったように、彼らは彼らです
territorial idea of border
国境という領土観念
Then they were in the previous life
それから彼らは前世にいた
For the current new ruler in group affairs
グループ問題における現在の新しい支配者にとって
It's the Chinese Communist Party
それは中国共産党です
after unification
統一後
for this
このため
new leader new
新しいリーダー 新しい
political interference
政治的介入
their hearts are repulsive or
彼らの心は反発しているか、
like you just mentioned
あなたが今言ったように
They try to accept him
彼らは彼を受け入れようとします
I have these three questions
この3つの質問があります
ok seems
わかりました
The first question is funding
最初の質問は資金調達です
I can tell you it's expensive
高価だと言えます
What about the moving fields?
移動フィールドについてはどうですか？
What about a squatting field?
スクワットフィールドはどうですか？
not the same
不太一樣
that means you're going a lot
それはあなたがたくさん行くことを意味します
Then you have to go to a different place each time
そうなると毎回違う場所に行かなければなりません
Then I'm just like everyone
それなら私もみんなと同じだよ
This National Science Council talks about the International Economic Council
この国家学術会議は国際経済会議について話します
we are willing to spend
私たちは喜んで費やします
All kinds of things you have to find a way to put into your brain
あらゆる種類のことを脳に入れる方法を見つけなければなりません
find your funding
資金を見つけてください
That is to say, this kind of mobile field is indeed more expensive
つまり、この種のモバイル分野は実際にはより高価です
the second
二番目
that about you means i'm here
あなたについてということは、私がここにいるということです
they look at my question
彼らは私の質問を見ています
words to the gun column
銃のコラムへの言葉
They're all pretty cute
みんなとてもかわいいです
That is to say, they think Taiwanese are Han Chinese.
つまり、台湾人は漢民族だと思っているのです。
You are just like all Han people in mainland China
あなたたちは中国本土のすべての漢民族と同じです
Instead, it means I'm over there
代わりに、それは私がそこにいるということです
I give a very small example
非常に小さな例を挙げます
I speak Sichuan dialect to them all over there
私はそこにいる彼らに四川弁を話します
because they shot
彼らが撃ったから
Because the language of each place is very different
それぞれの場所で言語が大きく異なるため、
So they are together in Sichuan dialect
だから彼らは四川弁で一緒です
but the most convenient
でも一番便利なのが
I also use Sichuan dialect for the interview
インタビューでも四川弁を使います
I talked to him for a long time
私は彼と長い間話しました
The last time a friend of mine was laughing next to Gunzhu's
最後に私の友人がグンジュの隣で笑っていたのは
asked an old lady
老婦人が尋ねた
Said that Professor Wang came from Taiwan
王教授は台湾出身だそうです
tell you
教えてください
Sichuan dialect, why don't you find it strange?
四川弁、不思議だと思いませんか？
The old lady said, is he Han Chinese? Of course I want to speak Chinese
おばあさんは「彼は漢民族ですか？もちろん中国語を話したいです」と言いました。
Because Sichuanese they speak Chinese, but he is Han
四川人なので中国語を話しますが、彼は漢人です。
Of course I think there is something strange about Chinese
確かに中国語には何か変なところがあると思います
So I don't have that problem
だからそんな問題はないよ
And of course when I was doing fieldwork over there
もちろん、私が現地でフィールドワークをしていたときも
I do not engage with all academic institutions, localities, governments
私はすべての学術機関、地方自治体、政府とは関与しません
So let me teach you a wonderful feeling
だから素敵な気持ちを教えてあげましょう
I was probably lucky, I didn't arrange it on purpose
たぶん幸運だった、意図的に手配したわけではない
I first met a group of local model school teachers
地元のモデルスクール教師のグループに初めて会いました
Their students are scattered in all the township primary schools
彼らの生徒は町内のすべての小学校に散らばっている
So every time they take me to the countryside
だから田舎に連れて行ってもらうたびに
It's the teacher's teacher who brought his friend
友達を連れてきたのは先生の先生です
So my identity is very much helped by everyone
私のアイデンティティは皆さんにとても助けられています
so what's your last question?
それで最後の質問は何ですか？
to the ethnic minorities in mainland China
中国本土の少数民族に
That gunman is a very special
あのガンマンはとても特別だ
i can say this
私はこれを言うことができます
That is to say, because they are caught between Han and Tibetan
つまり、漢民族とチベット民族の間に挟まれているからである。
Then he is not a nation
それでは彼は国民ではない
He is a crowd of many small places
彼はたくさんの小さな場所の集まりです
In this way, when identifying and classifying
このように、識別して分類すると、
turned him into a pawn
彼を駒に変えた
So but the history of the Gunners is very important
しかし、ガナーズの歴史は非常に重要です
Because from the historical memory of China
中国の歴史的記憶から
It seems that some historians think
と考える歴史家もいるようです。
It seems that part of him has become the current Han Chinese
彼の一部が現在の漢民族になっているようです
Some of them became the present Tibetans
彼らの中には現在のチベット人になった人もいます
so this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いですね
That is to say, if you believe in that history
つまり、その歴史を信じるなら
Then the gunmen are there again
するとまたガンマンたちがやって来る
The existence of the gunman
ガンマンの存在
It seems to prove that history exists
歴史が存在することを証明しているようだ
everyone knows what it means
誰もがそれが何を意味するかを知っています
so why would there be
それではなぜ存在するのでしょうか
A group as small as 300,000
30万人ほどの小さなグループ
become a very important nation
非常に重要な国家になる
Because he proves that Han and Tibetan belong to one family
なぜなら彼は漢民族とチベット民族が一つの家族に属していることを証明したからである。
But for gunmen
しかしガンマンにとっては
they are also proud
彼らも誇りに思っています
this is the gun column
これは銃のコラムです
Of course he doesn't know the historical construction behind it
もちろん彼はその背後にある歴史的構造を知りません
what those
それらは何ですか
All he knows is that they are now one
彼が知っているのは、彼らが今ひとつになったことだけだ
The gun column under the great history
偉大な歴史の下にある砲柱
And I get another from a myth
そして、神話からもう一つ得たもの
you can tell
教えてもいいよ
they often talk
彼らはよく話します
Guangong is your ancestor
広公はあなたの先祖です
your god
あなたの神
Zhou Chang is our ancestor
周昌は私たちの祖先です
our god
我らの神
So he has a lot of local myths and legends
そのため、彼には地元の神話や伝説がたくさんあります
They all tell the story of Zhou Chang and the official
それらはすべて、周昌と役人の物語を語っています。
In fact, there is a myth
実は神話があるんです
That is to say, Zhou Chang thinks
つまり、周昌氏はこう考えます。
There are more and more Han Chinese here
ここには漢民族がますます増えています
feel bored
退屈を感じる
He wants to carry a big rock
彼は大きな石を運びたい
shut the gate
門を閉めてください
Don't let the Han people in
漢民族を入れないでください
He turned out to be a ghost
彼は幽霊だったことが判明した
great strength
大きな力
no mind
気にしない
and only at night
そして夜だけ
So when he was carrying a big rock
それで彼が大きな石を運んでいたとき
that official is very cunning
あの役人はとても狡猾だ
Basic Education for Officials and Officials
公務員および役人のための基礎教育
Zhou Chang just threw the stone and ran away
周昌は石を投げて逃げた
So now the Han people are still here
つまり、漢民族は今もここにいます
that's all
それで全部です
So what I mean by this joke is that
このジョークで私が言いたいのは、
even if it's a joke
たとえそれが冗談だと​​しても
even a myth
神話さえ
his appearance
彼の外見
There is an image behind him
彼の後ろに像があります
The original image is the expression of their feelings
そのイメージは彼らの感情の表現です
he still feels
彼はまだ感じています
as if he accepts himself on the one hand
まるで自分自身を受け入れているかのように
The edge given to him by the Han
漢が彼に与えた優位性
image of minorities
マイノリティのイメージ
Strong and brainless
強くて頭脳がない
On the one hand, he thinks that the Han people are cunning
一方で、彼は漢民族が狡猾であると考えている
We can't beat the Chinese
中国人には勝てない
so we have to be like this
だから私たちはこうならなければいけない
But from other myths
しかし、他の神話から
he told me again
彼はまた私に言った
he said look
彼は言った、見てください
That Zhou Chang of yours is holding a Daguan knife
あなたの周昌は大関ナイフを持っています
Why did he choose Zhou Chang?
なぜ彼は周昌を選んだのでしょうか？
is very meaningful
とても意味のあることです
Zhou Chang is holding a Daguan knife
周昌は大関ナイフを持っています
standing behind the Han
漢の後ろに立っている
he means
彼が意味するのは
He said you Chinese
彼はあなたは中国人だと言いました
We are standing with the Han people
私たちは漢民族とともにいます
We are different from those Western Fans
私たちは西洋のファンとは違います
That Xi Fan is independent
シーファンは独立しているということ
Xifan refers to the Tibetan
西凡とはチベット人のことを指します
Because they often hear Tibetans seeking independence
チベット人が独立を求める声をよく聞くからです。
so at this time
だからこの時点では
He has
彼は持っています
He wants to choose a side, he is sandwiched between Han and Tibetan
彼はどちら側につくかを選びたがっている、彼は漢族とチベット族の間に挟まれている
So he chose to go out of state
そこで彼は州外へ行くことを選んだ
We are standing with the Han people
私たちは漢民族とともにいます
then speak more exaggeratedly
それならもっと大袈裟に話す
You see, you Han officials still need our protection
ほら、漢族の役人たちはまだ私たちの保護が必要です
We stand behind him with big knives
私たちは大きなナイフを持って彼の後ろに立っています
So you from these myths and legends
だからあなたはこれらの神話や伝説から
or some popular local images
または人気のある地元の画像
In fact, they are all signs
実際、それらはすべて兆候です
Regardless of the history I just analyzed earlier
先ほど分析した歴史とは関係なく
These myths and legends that I am telling now
私が今語る神話と伝説
or images are actually the same
または画像は実際に同じです
what i promote
私が宣伝していること
Then what I want to advocate is
そこで私が主張したいのは、
How do we learn from these representational phenomena
これらの表象現象から私たちはどのように学ぶのか
Inside to see the real side
内側から本当の側面を見てみましょう
return some of the emotions in it
そこにある感情の一部を返す
Hello Mr. Wang
こんにちは、王さん
my question is
私の質問は
China was a unified country during the Qin and Han Dynasties
中国は秦と漢の時代に統一国家でした
Then the Western Roman Empire
その後、西ローマ帝国が
It is also a unified empire
統一帝国でもある
Well, after China's continuous division
さて、中国の継続的な分裂の後
It will also revert to the situation where the unity
また、団結した状態に戻ります。
But after the division of the West, it became countless small countries
しかし、西洋の分裂の後、それは無数の小国になりました
This phenomenon is caused by the use of
この現象は使用によって引き起こされます。
Apart from geographical factors
地理的要因とは別に
this problem is too big
この問題は大きすぎます
I really have no way to answer
本当に答えようがありません
But I'm thinking of having a
でも、私は、
I think I think it's the same wherever I say it
どこで言っても同じだと思う
This is what I said in mainland China and Taiwan
これは中国本土や台湾で私が言ったことです
From the point of view of human ecology
人間生態学の観点から
If you take the whole of Eurasia
ユーラシア大陸全体を取ると
cut in half
半分に切ります
Half of them are from China
そのうち半数は中国から来た人だ
Emphasis on diversity
多様性の重視
Put all Xinjiang and Tibet in one big China
新疆とチベットをすべて一つの大きな中国に収める
the other side is
向こう側は
There are several very rich and powerful small countries along the coast
海岸沿いには非常に豊かで強力な小国がいくつかあります
in France, Germany, England, etc.
フランス、ドイツ、イギリスなどで
Then the inland is often involved
それから内陸部も絡んでくることが多いです
In this chaos of ethnicity, gender, religion, etc.
民族、性別、宗教などが入り乱れるこの混沌の中で。
Then everyone saw the recent large number of refugees
それから誰もが最近の大量の難民を目にしました
flee to the east
東へ逃げる
If everyone was a scholar of modern history
もしも誰もが近現代史学者だったら
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
At that time Sun Yat-sen and many of these revolutionaries
当時、孫文と多くの革命家は
early revolution this home
革命の初期 この家
also advocates building a very small China
非常に小さな中国の建設も主張している
And leave Mongolia, Tibet, and all Xinjiang outside
そしてモンゴル、チベット、そして新疆全域を外へ出て行け
If a China like this was established at that time
もしあの時こんな中国が建国していたら
in that human ecology
その人間の生態の中で
I think it's still the same today
それは今も同じだと思う
Refugees are not only running to the west but also to the east
難民は西だけでなく東にも逃げている
So in terms of human ecology, I think the eastern half
人間の生態学的観点から言えば、東半分は
So far it looks like it's better than the western half
今のところ西半分よりは良いようです
But overall
しかし全体的には
still too far away
まだ遠すぎる
That is to say, the whole so-called pluralism issue in China
つまり、中国におけるいわゆる多元主義問題全体が
There are still many problems inside
内部にはまだ多くの問題があります
to solve
解決する
Thanks
ありがとう
Im honest, Im a student who has studied the Chinese language of the teacher in animals before.
正直に言うと、私は動物の先生の中国語を以前に勉強した学生です。
The one who saw the teacher before
以前先生に会った人
At the edge of China, first recruit people from the teacher
中国の片隅で、まず先生から人を募る
The previous part is very incomprehensible
前の部分が非常にわかりにくい
But the more I read the teacher's book, the more interesting I find it.
しかし、先生の本は読めば読むほど面白くなります。
Especially when the teacher talked about Taiwan in the last piece
特に最後の作品で先生が台湾について話したときは
The teacher mentioned in it
その中で先生が言及していた
Because that book was written by the teacher at the end of the Twenty-Four Classics
あの本は古典二十四篇の最後に先生が書いたものだから
Then it mentioned some of the status of Taiwan's aboriginal research at that time
次に、当時の台湾の先住民研究の状況についていくつか触れました。
Especially in the past two years, it seems that it is more and more easy to see on the Internet that there is a saying
特にここ2年ほどで、こんな格言があることがネット上で目につくことが多くなったように感じます。
Think that the vast majority of people in Taiwan are descendants of the poor
台湾人の大多数は貧しい人々の子孫だと思う
In fact, I re-read the teacher's book recently, and I feel very emotional
実は最近先生の本を読み返して、とても感動しました
Is there any way for many teachers to make some expansions for this place?
多くの教師がこの場所を拡張する方法はありますか?
Thanks
ありがとう
This is what happens all over the world
これは世界中で起こっていることです
I think everyone just often has some imagination
誰もが想像力を持っていることが多いと思います
Imagine who our main thread is
私たちのメインスレッドが誰であるかを想像してください
In fact, he is showing a reality
実際、彼は現実を見せている
Sometimes we don't need to pay too much attention
あまり注意を払う必要がない場合もあります
or to criticize the imagination
あるいは想像力を批判する
or constructed history
あるいは構築された歴史
I think what we should do instead
代わりに何をすべきか考えます
is to analyze this imagination
この想像力を分析することです
what is this emotion or intention behind it
この感情やその背後にある意図は何ですか
This time my answer to your question
今回はあなたの質問に対する私の答えです
Well, today we are very, very grateful to Academician Wang
さて、今日は王学者に非常に感謝しています。
give us such a wonderful speech
とても素晴らしいスピーチをしてください
Answered many, many questions
たくさんの質問に答えました
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
Falcon
ファルコン